(light music)
（轻音乐）
- [Announcer] Stanford University.
-[播音员]斯坦福大学。
- [Instructor] Hello everybody and welcome,
-[老师]大家好，欢迎光临，
Stanford CS193p Spring of 2020.
斯坦福CS193p 2020年春季。
This is lecture three.
这是第三讲。
I'm gonna start today with a demo,
我今天将从演示开始，
demo of that reactive SwiftUI stuff we were talking about.
我们正在讨论的反应式SwiftUI内容的演示。
Then I am gonna jump into some slides,
然后我要跳一些幻灯片，
talk a little bit more about the Swift type system,
多说一些Swift类型的系统，
specifically protocols,
特别是协议
and then kind of a totally different topic after that,
然后是一个完全不同的话题，
which is the layout system for Views,
这是视图的布局系统，
how they get laid out on screen.
它们如何在屏幕上布置。
If time permits,
如果时间允许，
I'll actually do a little demo of that layout stuff
我实际上将对该布局进行一些演示
at the end of today.
在今天结束时。
If not, that'll be pushed to next time.
如果没有，它将被推迟到下一次。
And next time we're definitely going
下次我们一定要去
to lay out our cards in rows and columns
在行和列中排列我们的卡片
instead of all in a horizontal line like they are now.
而不是像现在这样水平排列。
And we'll also get started on actually having our Model
我们还将开始实际拥有我们的模型
play the game and implementing some of our logic.
玩游戏并实现我们的一些逻辑。
But for now, let's do this reactive Swift demo.
但是现在，让我们来做这个反应式Swift演示。
You're all really familiar now,
你们现在真的很熟悉
hopefully, with MVVM,
希望借助MVVM，
but before I start with this demo,
但是在我开始这个演示之前，
I'm gonna take just a quick second
我要花一秒钟
to review it just in case,
以防万一，
maybe it's been a few days since you did your homework.
也许距离您做完作业已经过了几天。
Here is our Model,
这是我们的模型，
it's called MemoryGame.
它称为MemoryGame。
It has this don't care CardContent
它有这个不在乎CardContent
which is what's on the card,
卡上有什么
which as a Model we don't care.
作为模型，我们不在乎。
That's up to the UI to decide
这取决于用户界面
what it wants to show on the cards.
它想在卡片上显示什么。
Here are our cards.
这是我们的卡。
This is an Array of this Card struct right down here.
这是此Card结构的数组。
And this choose lets us essentially play the game.
这种选择使我们可以玩游戏。
We haven't implemented any of that yet
我们还没有实现
but when you choose a card,
但是当您选择一张卡时，
that's when the matching happens and things like that.
那就是匹配发生的时间，诸如此类。
And here's how we initialize
这是我们初始化的方式
or create our MemoryGame.
或创建我们的MemoryGame。
We obviously wanna specify
我们显然想指定
how many pairs of cards in our game,
我们的游戏中有几副牌，
and we need a cardContentFactory function here
我们需要一个cardContentFactory函数
to make the content that's on the card
制作卡片上的内容
because for us, it's a don't care.
因为对我们来说，这不在乎。
So somebody who does care has to make that for us.
因此，需要照顾的人必须为我们做到这一点。
And here's our ViewModel.
这是我们的ViewModel。
Our ViewModel has a var which is the Model.
我们的ViewModel有一个var就是Model。
Our ViewModel can talk to the Model all at once.
我们的ViewModel可以一次与模型对话。
It's a portal or doorway onto the Model for the View
它是视图模型的门户或门口
so it has to be able to do that.
因此它必须能够做到这一点。
Notice that there are no vars in here to point to the View.
请注意，这里没有指向视图的变量。
The ViewModel never talks to its View.
ViewModel从不与它的View对话。
It's the View that talks to the ViewModel.
是与ViewModel对话的View。
And we're gonna see how the View
我们将看看
and the ViewModel kind of Interact in just a moment here,
和ViewModel互动，只需片刻
but there's never gonna be
但永远不会
any connectivity from the ViewModel to the Views
从ViewModel到View的任何连接
because many, many different Views
因为很多很多不同的观点
will be using this ViewModel,
将使用此ViewModel，
this portal, this doorway, onto the Model.
这个门户，这个门，进入模型。
They'll be using it, sharing it.
他们将使用它，共享它。
Again, that's why our ViewModel is a class.
同样，这就是为什么我们的ViewModel是一个类。
It's a pointer into something in the heap.
它是指向堆中某物的指针。
It's easy to share something that's pointed to.
分享指向的内容很容易。
So our ViewModel also provides
所以我们的ViewModel也提供
public access to the Model which is otherwise private.
对模型的公共访问，否则为私有。
And that access is both getting information,
而且访问都在获取信息，
like getting the cards and also letting
喜欢拿卡，也让
the View express its Intent,
视图表达其意图，
in this case, to choose a card.
在这种情况下，要选择一张卡。
Both very easily implemented by us with our Model
两者都非常容易通过我们的模型实施
but this is what our ViewModels job is.
但这就是我们的ViewModels工作。
And finally we have our View.
最后，我们有自己的观点。
We have two Views in our View in the MVVM View sense.
在MVVM视图意义上，我们的视图中有两个视图。
One is a View that represents a single card
一个是代表一张卡片的视图
and then this View,
然后这个视图
which is all of our cards combined here.
这是我们所有卡片的总和。
And based on the feedback that I got from some of you
根据我从你们中得到的反馈
working on your homework assignments this week,
这周做功课，
I wanna clarify a little bit,
我想澄清一点，
our thinking by clarifying
通过澄清我们的想法
the words we use to describe things.
我们用来形容事物的词。
A number of you were saying things like,
你们当中有些人在说
oh, I'm using this function to set the font of my card.
哦，我正在使用此功能设置卡的字体。
And while I guess that's not exactly not right,
虽然我认为这是不正确的，
really a better way of saying it is
真的是一个更好的说法
that this function right here
这个功能在这里
modifies the View we send it to,
修改我们发送到的视图，
so that it uses this font to draw.
以便使用此字体进行绘制。
And what's the difference there?
那有什么区别？
Well, it's the difference between declarative programming
嗯，这是声明式编程之间的区别
and imperative programming.
和命令式编程。
In declarative we're just declaring
在声明中，我们只是在声明
that this is the font that is used to draw this View,
这是用于绘制此视图的字体，
whereas in imperative, you're thinking things like,
而当务之急是，您在想诸如此类的事情，
oh, I'm calling this function
哦，我叫这个功能
to set the font at a certain moment in time,
在某个时刻设置字体，
I'm setting it.
我正在设置。
And there's no moment in time with this declarative.
并且没有及时使用此声明。
At any moment in time,
在任何时候，
this should draw the View that reflects the Model
这应该绘制反映模型的视图
and it should be able to do
它应该能够做到
that any time this body is requested.
任何时候要求这个机构。
Boom, it should be a View that reflects
景气，应该是反映
the state of the Model, essentially time insensitive.
模型的状态，本质上是时间不敏感的。
One other thing about this body is that this var,
关于这个身体的另一件事是这个变种，
you never access this var.
您永远不会访问此变量。
This lower body is never gonna appear in your code.
下半身永远不会出现在您的代码中。
This body is called by the system.
该主体由系统调用。
Every time the system wants to draw
每当系统想要绘制时
a View of the Model that this represents,
代表的模型视图，
it will call this var to get that View.
它将调用此变量以获取该视图。
So this is called by the system.
因此，这由系统调用。
Your job is to implement it by declaring what the View is,
您的工作是通过声明View是什么来实现它，
given the current state of the Model
给定模型的当前状态
that you see through this portal, the ViewModel.
通过该门户ViewModel看到的
And the last thing I wanna talk about
我想说的最后一件事
is some people were inside these ViewBuilders,
这些ViewBuilder中有一些人，
like in ForEach or even inside ZStack or HStack.
例如在ForEach中，甚至在ZStack或HStack中。
Remember these are ViewBuilders and ViewBuilders are cool
记住这些是ViewBuilders，而ViewBuilders很酷
because they're functions that return a View
因为它们是返回View的函数
and they do allow this limited if then
而且他们确实允许这种限制
and they allow you to just list Views
他们允许您只列出视图
instead of having to put them in an Array or something,
而不是必须将它们放入数组之类的东西中，
you can list them.
您可以列出它们。
People were wanting to put a var here,
人们想在这里放一个变种，
var x equals something down here.
var x在这里等于某物。
And of course you cannot create vars inside the ViewBuilder.
当然，您不能在ViewBuilder中创建var。
Vars can not be created inside these ViewBuilders,
无法在这些ViewBuilder中创建变量，
just not allowed to create vars.
只是不允许创建var。
So how do you do it?
你是怎么做到的？
There's two ways to do it.
有两种方法可以做到这一点。
One, you can put vars outside the ViewBuilders,
第一，您可以将vars放在ViewBuilders之外，
just in your normal function,
只是在正常的功能上
and then I could use x inside here.
然后我可以在这里使用x
But of course if I do that now, I've created this two line,
但是，如果我现在这样做的话，我已经创建了这两行，
I'll have to say return ZStack,
我不得不说返回ZStack，
but that's okay, I could do that.
没关系，我可以做到。
Another way, and probably a more common way,
另一种方法，也许是更常见的方法
is to create another,
是创造另一个，
let's say this wants to be an Int, computed property,
假设这想成为一个Int计算属性，
and just return whatever the value you want x to be
并只返回您希望x为的任何值
and now you can use x in here.
现在您可以在此处使用x
And it's just going to use this computed property
它只是要使用这个计算属性
to calculate the value of x that it wants.
计算它想要的x的值。
So that's the way we deal
这就是我们处理的方式
with essentially creating local variables or variables
本质上创建局部变量或变量
that we need to do our drawing in here.
我们需要在这里画图。
And this is currently called ContentView,
这目前称为ContentView，
by the way, because that's where we started
顺便说一句，因为那是我们开始的地方
with that template from Xcode.
使用Xcode中的模板。
Xcode didn't know we were doing a memory game at the time
Xcode当时不知道我们在做一个记忆游戏
so it called it ContentView.
因此将其称为ContentView。
Thought before we started,
在我们开始之前就想过
I would show you how we could rename that
我会告诉你如何重命名
to be a much better name.
成为一个更好的名字。
Now you might be tempted to do this in the navigator
现在您可能会想在导航器中执行此操作
with the search and replace feature here.
使用此处的搜索和替换功能。
And you can do that by going here to replace,
您可以通过替换此处来做到这一点，
and then you could search, for example,
然后您可以搜索例如
for ContentView and it would find
对于ContentView，它将发现
all the places it's referenced,
它所引用的所有地方，
then you could replace it with something
那么你可以用一些东西代替它
like EmojiMemoryGameView or something like that.
例如EmojiMemoryGameView或类似的东西。
But actually, this is not how we would do this.
但是实际上，这不是我们要做的。
If we're gonna change the name of a var or of a type,
如果我们要更改var或类型的名称，
we are gonna use refactoring.
我们将使用重构。
So the way we do that is we're gonna hold down
所以我们要做的就是压低
the Command key, Command + Click.
Command键，Command +单击。
And when we Command + Click,
当我们按下Command +单击时，
we get this nice menu here
我们在这里得到这个不错的菜单
where we can jump to the definition of a type
在这里我们可以跳转到类型的定义
or a var or something.
或var之类的东西。
We can also rename.
我们也可以重命名。
So we do that Command + Click,
因此，我们执行Command +单击，
and we're gonna go rename.
我们将重命名。
And it's showing us here all the places
它向我们展示了所有地方
that it found ContentView,
它发现了ContentView，
essentially the same thing as we did the search over here.
本质上与我们在此处进行搜索相同。
Some of them is gonna change,
其中一些会改变，
and you can tell with this little check mark,
你可以用这个小勾号告诉
thing's just gonna change.
事情将会改变。
So it's going to change this file name,
因此，它将更改此文件名，
so it's gonna change the name of that, that's good.
因此，它将要更改其名称，这很好。
Here it's showing the comment ContentView
这里显示了评论ContentView
but it's not gonna change that.
但这不会改变。
You see it's not blue, it's gray.
您会看到它不是蓝色，而是灰色。
It's just saying, I found this,
只是说，我发现了这个，
but I'm not gonna change that
但我不会改变
'cause I'm not sure that that's really referring
因为我不确定那真的是指
to this type since it's in a comment.
这种类型，因为它在注释中。
So we'll have to change that ourselves.
所以我们必须自己改变它。
It's gonna change down here this var preViews.
这个var preViews将会在这里改变。
That was actually that code
那实际上就是那个代码
we scrolled out of the way at the very beginning that shows
我们在显示的一开始就滚开了
our ContentView in the gray preview window over here,
我们的ContentView在此处的灰色预览窗口中，
so that obviously would need to be changed.
因此显然需要进行更改。
And then here's the code in the scene delegate
这是场景委托中的代码
where we're actually creating our memory game
我们实际上在创建记忆游戏的地方
and then passing it into this top level ContentView.
然后将其传递到此顶级ContentView中。
So when you do this Command + Click and rename,
因此，当您执行Command +单击并重命名时，
it actually selects what you Command + Clicked on
它实际上会选择您要执行的命令并单击
and you can just type something new.
您可以输入新内容。
So EmojiMemoryGameView, and see,
所以EmojiMemoryGameView，看看
it's changing it in all the other places, not here though.
它正在其他所有地方都在改变它，尽管不在这里。
And that's it.
就是这样。
So you just hit this rename right here
所以你就在这里点击这个重命名
and it has renamed it,
它已经重命名了，
even the name of the file over here is nicely renamed.
即使是这里的文件名也被很好地重命名。
And we can go back and fix the things
我们可以回去修复这些东西
that it wasn't sure about,
不确定
things like comments right here,
诸如评论之类的东西，
say, this is our EmojiMemoryGameView.swift which in fact
例如，这是我们的EmojiMemoryGameView.swift
is the name of this file.
是此文件的名称。
So that was just a little aside for renaming
所以这只是重命名的一小部分
'cause sometimes you'll pick a name
因为有时候你会选一个名字
for a type or a var and then you'll decide,
类型或变量，然后您将决定
I don't really like that name, it's not,
我真的不喜欢那个名字，不是，
because naming is really, really, really important.
因为命名真的非常非常重要。
Can't overemphasize how important it is
不能过分强调它的重要性
to pick good names for things.
为事物取好名字。
So being able to rename after you change your mind,
因此，当您改变主意后能够重命名，
really, really important.
非常非常重要
Our topic today though is going to be this reactive.
但是，今天我们的话题将是这种反应。
I told you that SwiftUI is reactive.
我告诉你SwiftUI是反应式的。
What do I mean by reactive?
反应是什么意思？
I mean that when changes happen in the Model,
我的意思是，当模型发生变化时，
they automatically are going to show up in the View.
它们将自动显示在“视图”中。
And currently our UI is not reactive.
目前，我们的用户界面还没有反应。
So that's a problem.
所以这是一个问题。
And let's take a look and see how we can fix that problem
让我们看看如何解决该问题
and make it so it is reactive.
并使其具有反应性。
We're not gonna implement our entire memory game here
我们不会在这里实现整个记忆游戏
with all the Card matching.
与所有匹配的卡片。
We're just gonna take a baby step forward
我们只是要向前迈出一步
which is we're gonna make the cards flip over.
这就是我们要使卡片翻转的原因。
That's part of our Model.
这是我们模型的一部分。
Essentially the first step of our game logic
本质上是我们游戏逻辑的第一步
is to have a card,
是要有一张卡，
when we choose it, flip over.
当我们选择它时，翻过来。
So I've moved over here to my Model code
所以我已经移到了我的模型代码
where currently we just say card chosen
目前我们只说选择的卡片
when you touch on a card,
当您触摸卡片时，
remember that from last time.
记得从上次开始。
Now I wanna start actually implementing my game logic
现在我想开始实际实现我的游戏逻辑
starting with flipping the card over.
首先将卡翻转过来。
Now you'll look at this and you'll think,
现在，您将看到这个，然后您会认为，
oh, this is easy.
哦，这很容易。
Card.isFaceUp equals not card.isFaceUp, right?
Card.isFaceUp等于不等于card.isFaceUp，对吗？
Somebody is passing us the card
有人通过我们的卡
they wanna choose as an argument
他们想选择一个参数
and I'm just going to have this face upness of it
我只是要面对它
be toggled or flipped to its opposite here.
在这里被切换或翻转到相反的方向。
And this has an error which is that,
这是一个错误，
Cannot assign to property.
无法分配给属性。
Card is a let constant.
卡是一个让常量。
Which it is all arguments to functions are essentially let.
函数的所有参数本质上都是允许的。
You don't type that let, but they are a let.
您不键入该让，但它们是一个让。
So that's one problem.
这是一个问题。
But it's actually much, much worse than that.
但这实际上比这糟得多。
It's not just that this is a let.
这不只是让它出租。
This is a Card.
这是一张卡。
A Card is a struct.
卡是一种结构。
Structs are value types as we talked about last time.
结构是我们上次谈到的值类型。
And a value type, remember, is copied every time
记住，每次都会复制一个值类型
it's passed as a parameter to a function
它作为参数传递给函数
or even assigned to another variable copy, copy, copy.
甚至分配给另一个变量副本，副本，副本。
It's always being copied.
它总是被复制。
So this Card here is a copy of one of the Cards here.
所以这里的这张卡是这里一张卡的副本。
The new ViewModel got it or hand it out to a View
新的ViewModel将其获取或分发给View
and when the View got it, it was a copy,
当视图获得时，它就是副本，
maybe even a copy of a copy.
甚至一个副本。
So this is not actually a Card that's in the Array,
所以这实际上不是阵列中的Card，
it's a copy of that.
这是一个副本。
Every time we pass a value type, it gets copied.
每次我们传递值类型时，它都会被复制。
So even if we could do this,
所以即使我们可以做到
which we can't because of that problem where this
我们不能因为那个问题而在这里
is all essentially a let,
本质上是一个让，
it wouldn't be doing the right thing anyway.
无论如何，这不会做对的事情。
This would just be changing this guy to its space up
这只会改变这个家伙的空间
to be swapped is having no effect on this one right here.
被交换对这里的这个没有影响。
So let's try something totally different here.
因此，让我们在这里尝试完全不同的东西。
Let's try and find out the index
让我们尝试找出索引
of which Card in this Array that this card is.
该卡在此阵列中的哪个卡。
I'm gonna do that by saying let chosenIndex,
我要说的是letedIndex，
which is gonna be a type Int,
这将是Int类型，
I'm gonna equal to,
我等于
I'm gonna call a function on myself, index of that card.
我要给自己调用一个函数，该卡的索引。
So index of I'm gonna write a function,
所以索引我要写一个函数，
it's gonna be a function in myself of this card.
这将是这张卡的功能。
So I'm gonna find this card,
所以我要找到这张卡
find out what index it is in this Array.
找出它在此数组中的索引。
So you have func index of which is gonna be a type Card,
因此，您具有的func索引将成为类型Card，
it's gonna return an Int,
它会返回一个Int，
and this Int is going to be the index into this Array.
并且此Int将成为此Array的索引。
Now maybe I would say let chosenCard,
现在也许我会说让letedCard，
which is gonna be a type Card,
这将是类型卡
equal my cards at that chosenIndex.
在那个selectedIndex等于我的牌。
It sounds good.
这听起来不错。
Now I can say now let's flip the card over,
现在我可以说现在让我们翻转卡片，
isFaceUp equals not chosenCard.isFaceUp.
isFaceUp等于未选择Card.isFaceUp。
So this seems like this is a good idea,
所以这似乎是个好主意，
we'll have to implement this in a minute,
我们将在一分钟内实现它，
but this seems like this will be great.
但这似乎很棒。
Now, we are getting a Card out of the Array
现在，我们从阵列中取出卡
and we're flipping it over.
我们将其翻转过来。
But this too is not gonna work for exactly the same reason.
但这也不会出于完全相同的原因而起作用。
When we make an assignment to a var, this chosen Card,
当我们分配一个变种给这个选择的卡片时，
this equals copies this out of here.
这等于将其复制到此处。
It copies the Card out of the Array.
它将卡从阵列中复制出来。
So even just making an assignment
所以即使只是做一个作业
to another variable copies a value type.
到另一个变量将复制值类型。
So now you're probably like,
所以现在您可能会喜欢
well, how are we gonna change this thing?
好吧，我们将如何改变这个东西？
Well, we have to change it in place.
好吧，我们必须对其进行更改。
Instead of changing a copy of this thing here,
而不是在这里更改此副本，
we're going to change this Array itself,
我们将要更改此数组本身，
this Array of Cards,
这一系列的卡片，
we're going to reach in there and change whichever
我们将到达那里并改变任何一个
is the right Card to be the different FaceUp.
是适合作为不同FaceUp的卡片。
So we're gonna do that.
所以我们要去做。
Still going to do self.cards chosenIndex,
仍然要做self.cards selectedIndex，
but instead of this indirection through a var
但不是通过var进行这种间接
that would copy it,
那会复制它，
I'm just going to have that thing directly
我将直接拥有那个东西
is FaceUp equal not that thing directly isFaceUp.
FaceUp等于不是那个东西直接是FaceUp。
So I'm just gonna flip the Card over,
所以我要把卡片翻过来
directly inside the Array.
直接在数组内部。
A couple of things going on here.
这里发生了几件事。
One, notice I'm putting self.in front
一，注意我把self。放在前面
of every access to my variables
对我的变量的每次访问
and to functions I'm calling on myself.
和功能，我呼吁自己。
This self.is optional in the vast majority of cases.
在大多数情况下，此self。是可选的。
And normally I would even say, don't put it there.
通常我什至会说，不要把它放在那里。
It's just extra prompt.
这只是额外的提示。
However, because of this thing I talked about last time
但是，由于这个原因，我上次谈到
where they're going to make it,
他们要去哪里
so even in the few cases
所以即使在少数情况下
where you do need a self.,
您确实需要自我的地方。
like here, self.is actually required
像这里，self。实际上是必需的
in our View when we did our tap gesture, this self.,
在我们的视图中，当我们进行点击手势时，这个自我。
if you take this away,
如果把这个拿走
it's gonna have an error,
会有错误，
you have to fix it, remember that?
您必须修复它，还记得吗？
So they're gonna take this away.
所以他们要把这个拿走。
And when they take that away,
当他们拿走那东西时，
then you're gonna need self.almost nowhere.
那么您将需要自我。几乎无处。
So at that point,
所以在那个时候
I don't know if that's two months from now,
我不知道那是两个月后
it's not clear,
还不清楚
WWDC is at the beginning of June.
WWDC是在六月初。
A lot of times they'll come out
很多时候他们会出来
with new software, beta software,
使用新软件，测试版软件，
at least at that point,
至少在那时
maybe they'll fix it then, I don't know.
也许他们会解决的，我不知道。
I don't work at Apple,
我不在苹果公司工作
I don't know anything what their plans are,
我不知道他们的计划是什么，
but we do know that it's been publicly approved
但我们确实知道它已被公开批准
to get rid of this self..
摆脱自我
So in this course,
所以在这个过程中
just for the next seven or eight weeks left in this course,
仅在本课程剩下的七八周内，
I kind of recommend maybe just putting
我有点推荐也许只是把
self.in front of everything
自我在一切面前
because it doesn't hurt anything
因为它不会伤害任何东西
and it'll keep you from running into this problem
这样可以避免您遇到此问题
where you have to do the fix it.
您必须在哪里进行修复。
You're just learning this stuff and that's going to kind of
您只是在学习这些东西，这将会
give you the muscle memory of always typing self.
带给您经常打字自我的肌肉记忆。
which you'll have to train yourself out of
您必须训练自己
in a couple of months when this public fix comes out.
在此公开修复程序发布后的几个月内。
But it'll keep you out of trouble in this quarter.
但这会让您在本季度摆脱困境。
So that's my recommendation
那是我的建议
but in your homework, we're not going to say,
但是在您的作业中，我们不会说
oh, that's wrong, you put self.,
哦，那是错误的，你把自己放了。，
or oh, that's wrong, you didn't put self..
或哦，那是错误的，你没有自我介绍。
That's totally up to you.
这完全取决于您。
I'm just trying to head off possible problems for you.
我只是想为您解决可能的问题。
So go for self.is probably my recommendation.
因此，自我追求可能是我的建议。
But (chuckles) we put this in here
但是（笑）我们把它放在这里
and we were sure this was gonna work.
而且我们确定这会成功。
We're for sure changing isFaceUp and that Array,
我们确定要更改isFaceUp和该数组，
there is no doubt self.cards of chosenIndex.
毫无疑问，selectedIndex的self.cards。
We are changing this Array to have it isFaceUp be toggled,
我们正在更改此数组以使其切换为isFaceUp，
and yet we still have an error here,
但是我们这里仍然有一个错误，
Cannot assign to property: self is immutable.
无法分配给属性：自我是不可变的。
It's not saying that this cards is immutable
并不是说这张卡是一成不变的
because the cards is not, it's a var.
因为卡不是，所以是变种。
If it were a let, it would be immutable,
如果放手，那将是一成不变的，
but it's a var so it's mutable,
但这是一个变种，所以是可变的，
but its self itself that is immutable.
但是它本身就是一成不变的。
In other words, our own function
换句话说，我们自己的功能
doesn't seem to be able to modify our self.
似乎无法改变我们的自我。
How do we do anything then if we can't do that?
如果我们做不到，那该怎么办呢？
Well, what's going on here
好吧，这是怎么回事
is that I told you these value types,
是我告诉你这些值类型
Swift is not doing a bitwise copy,
Swift没有做按位复制，
it's not actually copying them from one place in memory
实际上不是从内存中的一个位置复制它们
to another when you pass them around.
当您将它们传递给另一个时。
That's the semantic,
这就是语义
that's how you have to imagine it's happening,
那就是你要想象它正在发生的方式，
but it's really only actually making those copies
但这实际上只是制作这些副本
in memory when you start changing something,
当您开始更改某些内容时，
which we are doing here.
我们正在这里做。
We are changing this Array
我们正在改变这个数组
and this is our actual property,
这是我们的实际财产，
so we're not making a copy,
所以我们不复印
it's actually changing the Array,
实际上是在改变数组，
but this method changes our self.
但是这种方法改变了我们的自我。
It modifies our self
它改变了我们的自我
because it changes our cards.
因为它改变了我们的牌。
So we have to let Swift know that by saying
所以我们必须通过说让Swift知道这一点
that this is a mutating function.
这是一个变异函数。
So all functions that modify self
所以所有修改自我的功能
have to be marked mutating in a struct.
必须在结构中标记为变异。
This is not true in a class.
这在课堂上是不正确的。
Classes are in the heap.
类在堆中。
We have pointers to them.
我们有指向他们的指针。
We can always change things that are in the heap,
我们总是可以更改堆中的内容，
always modify things through a pointer,
总是通过指针修改事物，
which, as I talked about before,
正如我之前所说，
can be a bad thing just as much as a good thing.
可以和一件好事一样是一件坏事。
But for structs, no, because they're value types
但是对于结构，不，因为它们是值类型
we have to let Swift know we're changing this.
我们必须让Swift知道我们正在对此进行更改。
Now, index of, which we're gonna write in a second here,
现在，索引，我们将在这里写一秒钟，
it's just getting the index of a Card in this Array.
它只是获取此阵列中Card的索引。
It's not actually changing anything.
它实际上并没有改变任何东西。
It's just getting the index.
它只是获取索引。
So it does not need or want mutating here.
因此，它不需要或不想在这里进行变异。
And similarly or inversely,
同样或相反，
our initializer is implicitly changing our self.
我们的初始化器隐式地改变了我们的自我。
We're creating our self.
我们正在创造自我。
We're setting all of our variables here.
我们在这里设置所有变量。
So of course this is mutating,
所以这当然是变异的
so you don't say mutating in it.
所以你不用说变异了。
All inits are mutating.
所有的初始化都是变异的。
It's all part of the cool feature of value types
这都是价值类型很酷的功能的一部分
that Swift knows when they're changing.
Swift知道他们何时进行更改。
And you're gonna see that that has other benefits
而且您会发现它还有其他好处
other than just this copy
除了这个副本
on right behavior as we copy things around.
当我们复制事物时保持正确的行为。
Index of Card, how are we going to find out where this Card
卡的索引，我们如何找出该卡的位置
that we're getting the index of is in this Array?
我们得到的索引是在这个数组中？
We want the index into this Array that has this Card.
我们想要具有该卡的该数组的索引。
This turns out to be super easy for us
事实证明，这对我们来说超级容易
because Card is Identifiable.
因为卡是可识别的。
And since it's Identifiable,
由于它是可识别的，
we can just look at its ID
我们可以看看它的ID
and uniquely see which Card it is.
并唯一地查看它是哪张卡。
So we just need to do a little for loop here
所以我们只需要在这里做一些for循环
for index in zero dot dot less than our cards count,
如果零点索引的索引少于我们的卡数，
or again, if we're doing self dot,
还是再一次，如果我们正在做自我点，
self.cards.count, either way is perfectly fine.
self.cards.count，无论哪种方式都很好。
I'm just gonna go through every one
我只是要经历每一个
and I'm gonna say if self.cards at that index,
我要说的是self.cards在那个索引上
id equals this thing right here,
id在这里等于这个东西，
two equals, by the way,
顺便说一句，两个等于
of I guess, dot id, then I can return
我想，点号，那么我可以返回
this index 'cause I found it.
这个索引是因为我找到了它。
Here I'm looking at my Array
在这里，我正在看我的数组
to see if the index, if the Card at that index,
查看索引，如果卡片在该索引，
it's id is the same as this one you passed.
它的ID与您传递的ID相同。
Now, you can already see a problem here of really of.
现在，您已经可以在这里真正看到一个问题了。
we're gonna call this variable of, no.
我们将这个变量称为，不。
We don't wanna call this of.
我们不想这样称呼。
Of is just something that makes it nice for people
Of只是对人们有益的东西
who call us to say self index of card.
谁叫我们说卡的自我索引。
That's why we have this dual labeling
这就是为什么我们要使用双重标签
of external name, internal name.
外部名称，内部名称。
And that allows us to call this card dot id
这样我们就可以将此卡号称为ID
but callers still get to say index of card.
但是呼叫者仍然可以说出卡片索引。
This is a great example hopefully,
希望这是一个很好的例子，
totally see why we have external names
完全明白为什么我们有外部名称
and internal names of arguments.
和参数的内部名称。
We didn't do it here.
我们没有在这里做。
The external name and the internal name are the same.
外部名称和内部名称相同。
There's kind of an argument here
这里有点争论
you might actually put the under bar here on choose
您可能实际上选择了下栏
because it's clear that we're choosing a Card
因为很明显，我们正在选择一张卡
that's the type of this argument,
这就是这种说法的类型
what else would we choose anyway?
无论如何我们还会选择什么？
But I'm gonna leave it this way
但我要这样离开
just so we don't have to change our other code.
只是这样，我们不必更改其他代码。
But if you read the guidelines
但是如果您阅读指南
as part of your homework last week,
作为上周作业的一部分，
you'll see that this is one
您会看到这是一个
where maybe an under bar would be there
那里可能有一个酒吧
and then people would just take choose
然后人们会选择
and provide the Card is the argument,
并提供Card作为参数，
there would be no label for the callers.
呼叫者将没有标签。
We've done our for loop, we've found this.
我们已经完成了for循环，我们找到了这个。
What's still complaining here?
这里还在抱怨什么？
Missing return in a function expected return Int.
函数预期返回Int中缺少返回。
Oh yeah, what if this for loop goes all the way through
哦，是的，如果这个for循环一直进行下去
and never finds that Card?
却找不到那个卡？
Then we've gotta return something here.
然后我们必须在这里退货。
So Swift actually has a fantastic thing
所以Swift实际上有一件很棒的事情
to return here when this happens,
发生这种情况时返回这里
like you go to find something, you can't find it.
就像您去寻找东西一样，您找不到它。
In other languages,
用其他语言
you'd probably return minus one or some bogus thing here.
您可能会在这里退回一件或几件虚假物品。
I guess I'll return, maybe you'd return zero
我想我会回来，也许你会归零
which is the first element
这是第一个要素
which is totally wrong.
这是完全错误的。
If you go look for the Card and you can't find it,
如果您去找卡，却找不到它，
you're gonna say, well, return the first Card
你会说，好吧，归还第一张卡
even though you know that's not the Card.
即使您知道那不是卡。
So it doesn't really matter what we'll return here for now
所以我们现在回到这里并不重要
because this is all just wrong.
因为这都是错误的。
But I am gonna put a little thing
但是我要放一点东西
called a TODO here, and say bogus.
在这里叫一个TODO，然后说假的。
And a TODO is something you can go back later,
TODO是您以后可以回头的东西，
slash slash TODO,
斜线斜线TODO，
and find to remind yourself you need to fix this.
并提醒自己您需要解决此问题。
And these show up up here along the top
这些出现在顶部
where it says index up.
它说索引。
If you click,
如果单击
this is a list of all my vars and funcs,
这是我所有的变量和函数的列表，
look bogus appears right there.
看起来虚假出现在那儿。
And if I click on it, it takes me right to bogus.
如果我单击它，则需要我进行虚假验证。
And we will come back when I show you this cool way
当我向您展示这种很酷的方式时，我们会回来的
that you can return things
你可以退还东西
like I couldn't find it from Swift.
就像我在Swift中找不到它一样。
We're gonna cover that probably next lecture
我们将在下一次讲座中介绍
and we'll fix this, we'll fix this.
我们将修复此问题，我们将修复此问题。
But for now, we're gonna do this bogus thing right here.
但是现在，我们要在这里做这个假的事情。
So we have index of card.
所以我们有卡索引。
We are definitely flipping the Card over here.
我们绝对是在这里翻转卡。
So let's run and see if this is working.
因此，让我们运行，看看它是否有效。
'cause we know we already have this
因为我们知道我们已经有了这个
hooked up to choose a Card there.
钩在那里选择卡。
So now it should choose, say card chosen,
所以现在应该选择，例如选择卡片
and also flip it over, there we go.
然后将它翻转过来，就可以开始了
Ready, ghost.
准备好了，鬼。
Oh pumpkin.
哦，南瓜。
Well it's definitely accessing the Model here
好吧，这肯定是在这里访问模型
because we're getting this Card chosen.
因为我们正在选择这张卡。
But how come these cards are staying face up?
但是，这些卡为何面朝上呢？
What is going on here?
这里发生了什么？
Well, what's going on here
好吧，这是怎么回事
is we haven't implemented the reactive thing.
是我们还没有实施反应性的东西。
I told you at the start of this
我一开始就告诉你
that's why we're here today,
这就是为什么我们今天在这里，
is to do this reactive thing.
是要做这种反应性的事情。
And you can see why we need the reactive.
您会看到为什么我们需要反应堆。
We chose a card,
我们选择了一张卡，
it went here and changed the Model,
它去了这里，改变了模型，
it flipped a Card over,
它翻转了一张卡片，
and yet we didn't see anything in the UI.
但是我们在用户界面中什么都没有看到。
And never should that be the case in SwiftUI ever.
而且在SwiftUI中永远不会是这种情况。
When you change the Model, the UI should update.
更改模型时，UI应更新。
How do we make that happen?
我们如何做到这一点？
If you remember from my MVVM slides,
如果您记得我的MVVM幻灯片，
I put some keywords on the screen there
我在屏幕上放了一些关键字
and I said, oh, these Swift key words,
我说，哦，这些Swift关键字，
we're going to use those to do this reactive
我们将用那些来做这种反应
and that's exactly what we're gonna do right now.
而这正是我们现在要做的。
And we're gonna start in our ViewModel.
我们将从ViewModel开始。
So here's our ViewModel.
这是我们的ViewModel。
And the way we make the ViewModel participate
以及我们使ViewModel参与的方式
in this reactive thing is using a constrains
在这种反应性的东西中使用约束
and gains thing called ObservableObject.
并获得称为ObservableObject的东西。
Now remember constrains and gains,
现在记住限制和收获，
also known as protocols by the way.
也被称为协议。
These constrains and gains,
这些制约和收获，
we used one over here, colon View,
我们在这里用过一个，结肠视图，
that was a constrains and gains.
那是一个制约和收获。
We were kind of constrained
我们有点束缚
that we had to implement this body
我们必须实施这个机构
but we gained all these other functions
但是我们获得了所有其他功能
that we can send to View.
我们可以发送给View。
So this one was a huge gains
所以这是一个巨大的收获
for our very small constrains to do View here.
因为我们的限制很小，请点击此处查看。
We also did it in our Model, our card.
我们也在模型，卡片中做到了。
We did constraint and gains to be Identifiable,
我们做了一些限制，并取得了可识别的收益，
which required us to do this var id Int,
这要求我们执行此var id Int，
but now we gain the ability to tell which Card is which.
但是现在我们可以分辨哪张卡了。
And the UI is going to use that right here
UI将在此处使用
in this ForEach to make sure that if our cards move around
在此ForEach中，以确保我们的卡是否到处移动
or whatever, we can track where they are and animate them.
或其他方式，我们可以跟踪它们的位置并为其设置动画。
You're gonna see animation in SwiftUI,
您将在SwiftUI中看到动画，
it's ridiculously easy and a lot of it is
这非常容易，而且很多
because of this mechanism.
因为这种机制。
So this constrains and gains right here,
所以这就是制约和收获，
the constraints are almost none.
约束几乎没有。
You don't have to implement any vars or funcs,
您无需实现任何var或funcs，
no body or id or anything like that.
没有身体或身份证或类似的东西。
The tiny little constraint
微小的限制
is that it only works for classes, ObservableObject.
是它仅适用于ObservableObject类。
You can only be an ObservableObject here if you're a class,
如果您是班级，则只能在此处成为ObservableObject，
so that's minor constrains there.
所以那是次要的约束。
Now, the gain you get by doing this
现在，通过这样做您获得的收益
is you get this var called objectWillChange.
您是否获得了一个名为objectWillChange的变量。
This var right here,
这个变种就在这里，
you don't have to put it here like we did with body,
您不必像我们对身体那样把它放在这里，
you get it for free behind the scenes.
您可以在后台免费获得它。
So this will not be here.
所以这里不会。
I'm just showing it to you, what you're getting.
我只是向您展示您所得到的。
And this var is not really of this type,
而且这个var不是真正的这种类型，
ObservableObjectPublisher,
ObservableObjectPublisher，
it's a little more complicated than that.
比这复杂一点。
We don't even know or care what it is really
我们甚至不知道或不在乎它是什么
but there's two things about this var that we need to know.
但是我们需要了解有关此var的两件事。
One is that it's a Publisher,
一个是它是发布者，
meaning that it can publish to the world,
意味着它可以发布给全世界，
to anyone who's interested,
对任何有兴趣的人，
and our Views are going to be interested,
我们的观点将会引起人们的兴趣，
when something changes.
当某些变化。
And this var can only be sent one function
而且这个变数只能传送一个函数
which is the function send.
这是发送功能。
And if you call the function send on objectWillChange,
如果您调用该函数在objectWillChange上发送，
it's going publish to the world
它要发布给全世界
something changed about this object
这个物件有些改变
or really something will change very soon
否则很快就会改变
so get ready and then react to it.
所以准备好然后对它做出反应。
And that's it, that's all we have to do, really,
就是这样，这就是我们要做的，真的，
to have our ViewModel participate in this.
让我们的ViewModel参与其中。
So every time our Model changes,
所以每次我们的模型改变时
we want to do objectWillChange.send.
我们想要做objectWillChange.send。
For example, here's an Intent.
例如，这是一个意图。
Clearly we're changing our Model right here.
显然，我们正在此处更改模型。
We know that choose card
我们知道选择卡
is a mutable mutating function right here.
是一个可变的变异函数。
So of course that's going to change our Model.
因此，这当然会改变我们的模型。
So here we would just say objectWillChange.send.
所以在这里我们只说objectWillChange.send。
This is the only function, really,
实际上，这是唯一的功能
we're ever gonna call on
我们永远都在拜访
this objectWillChange thing right here.
这个objectWillChange东西就在这里。
And this is going to publish to the world,
这将要发布到全世界，
objectWillChange meaning this MemoryGame will change.
objectWillChange表示此MemoryGame将更改。
That's all, it's not saying how it changed, it changed.
仅此而已，不是说它是如何改变的，而是它的改变。
And that's important to know
这一点很重要
because if this ViewModel changed,
因为如果此ViewModel更改，
this portal on the Model has changed,
模型上的此门户已更改，
Views that are looking to
希望查看的视图
that portal need to redraw themselves.
该门户网站需要重绘。
And we're gonna show you in just a second
我们将在短短一秒钟内告诉您
how they sign up to do that.
他们如何注册才能做到这一点。
So again, we don't need to put this in here,
再说一次，我们不需要把它放在这里，
we get it for free.
我们免费获得它。
And when I get rid of that, you can see no errors.
而当我摆脱它时，您将看不到任何错误。
This is all perfectly legal.
这完全是合法的。
You can call this anytime you want,
您可以随时拨打此电话，
anytime something changes.
任何时候改变。
Doesn't even have to be your Model changing.
甚至不必改变您的模型。
If you were gonna change these emojis,
如果您要更改这些表情符号，
for example, you could call objectWillChange,
例如，您可以调用objectWillChange，
totally up to you.
完全取决于您。
However, in a significant app,
但是，在重要的应用中，
you're gonna have, possibly, a lot of Intents,
您可能会有很多意图，
a lot of different things that might change your Model.
许多可能会改变您的模型的不同事物。
And it's a little bit annoying
这有点烦人
to have to say objectWillChange.send,
不得不说objectWillChange.send，
objectWillChange.send.
objectWillChange.send。
It's even error prone.
甚至容易出错。
What if I oopsy daisy forgot to put this in there
如果我哎呀雏菊忘了把它放在那里
and then you choose a Card and it's like,
然后您选择一张卡片，就像
the cards still don't flip over, why?
卡仍然不翻转，为什么？
Because I forgot to put that in there.
因为我忘了把它放在那里。
So while we can call objectWillChange.send anytime we want,
因此，尽管我们可以随时调用objectWillChange.send，
usually the way we deal with this
通常我们处理这个问题的方式
is we take this var and we make it Published.
是我们采用此var并使其发布。
So this is not a Swift keyword,
所以这不是Swift关键字，
you can see it's not magenta,
你会看到它不是洋红色的
it's something called a property wrapper,
这就是所谓的属性包装器
this is a property.
这是一个财产。
And property wrappers add a little functionality
属性包装器增加了一些功能
around a property.
周围的财产。
In this case what this wrapper does
在这种情况下，这个包装器会做什么
is every time this property,
每次都是这个属性，
this Model, changes,
这个模型改变了，
it calls objectWillChange.send.
它调用objectWillChange.send。
That's what it does.
这就是它的作用。
So really, to make it so that our ObservableObject here,
确实如此，要使我们的ObservableObject在此处，
our ViewModel, broadcasts every time something changes,
我们的ViewModel会在每次发生变化时广播，
we just need to @Published all of our vars
我们只需要@Published我们所有的变量
that we care whether they change when in this case
我们关心在这种情况下它们是否会改变
it's just our one Model var.
这只是我们的一个Model var。
It could be other things as well.
也可能是其他事情。
You can have as many of these @Published vars as you want.
您可以根据需要拥有多个@Published变量。
Any time any of them change,
任何时候只要他们改变
it's going to objectWillChange.send,
这将是objectWillChange.send，
that's what it does.
这就是它的作用。
This looks all a lot nicer than having to remember
这看起来比记住要好得多
to put objectWillChange.send in all these functions.
将objectWillChange.send放入所有这些函数中。
You still have the option of doing objectWillChange.send
您仍然可以选择执行objectWillChange.send
even if you use these,
即使您使用这些，
but most of the time you will not have
但是大多数时候你不会
to do objectWillChange.send.
做objectWillChange.send。
So we're almost there.
所以我们快到了。
Right now we've got our ViewModel
现在我们有了ViewModel
so it's publishing every time the Model changes.
因此每次模型更改时都会发布。
Now we just need to fix our View over here
现在我们只需要在这里修复我们的视图
so that when it sees this ViewModel publishing, it redraws.
这样，当看到此ViewModel发布时，它将重新绘制。
Redraws every time it sees this thing,
每当看到这个东西时都会重画，
say objectWillChange.send.
说出objectWillChange.send。
And the way it does that is with another property wrapper
这样做的方法是使用另一个属性包装器
on this one called @ObservedObject.
在这个称为@ObservedObject的对象上。
And that's saying this var has an ObservableObject in it,
就是说这个var中有一个ObservableObject，
which it does, EmojiMemoryGame is an ObservableObject.
这样做，EmojiMemoryGame是一个ObservableObject。
And every time it says objectWillChange.send, redraw.
并且每当它说objectWillChange.send时，都要重画。
And of course redrawing this one is gonna cause this one
当然重画这个会导致这个
potentially to get redrawn as well.
也有可能被重画。
Now, you might kind of feel like,
现在，您可能会觉得，
whoa, this could be really inefficient,
哇，这可能效率很低，
what if the Model is changing all the time,
如果模型一直在变化，该怎么办？
are we gonna be redrawing our Views every single time?
我们是否会每次都重新绘制视图？
Well, yes and no.
好，是的，不是。
Yes, we're going to be reacting to objectWillChange
是的，我们将对objectWillChange做出反应
and redrawing, but SwiftUI is smart about seeing
和重绘，但是SwiftUI很聪明地看到了
whether something actually changed.
是否确实发生了变化。
So if we flip one card over,
因此，如果我们翻转一张卡，
it's not going to redraw every single card,
不会重提每张卡，
just the one that changed and it knows
只是一个改变了，它知道
because the Cards are Identifiable.
因为卡是可识别的。
You starting to see why this ForEach on this Array of Cards
您开始了解为什么在此卡阵列上此ForEach
forced us to make this Identifiable.
迫使我们对此进行识别。
It helps it to understand, oh, this one changed
有助于理解，哦，这个改变了
so I actually need to redraw that.
所以我实际上需要重画。
Because actually calling this code
因为实际上是在调用此代码
is probably not very expensive.
可能不是很贵。
Actually drawing on screen, that's pretty expensive.
实际上是在屏幕上绘图，这非常昂贵。
So SwiftUI does everything it can to avoid doing that.
因此，SwiftUI会尽一切可能避免这样做。
But conceptually for us, it's so simple.
但是从概念上讲，这很简单。
Every time our Model changes,
每当我们的模型改变时，
this @Published wrapper notices that,
@Published包装器注意到，
we're an ObservableObject,
我们是一个ObservableObject，
so our View can mark that it's interested in that publishing
因此我们的视图可以标记为对该发布感兴趣
and voila, it's gonna redraw this.
瞧，这会重绘。
And this is how we do reactive programming.
这就是我们进行反应式编程的方式。
Really, that's all there is to it.
真的，这就是全部。
We're gonna see some minor refinements
我们将看到一些小的改进
to that down the road,
到那边
but this is essentially how it works.
但这实际上就是它的工作方式。
So let's see if it works.
因此，让我们看看它是否有效。
Let's go run our app.
让我们运行我们的应用程序。
Hopefully when we click on the cards,
希望当我们点击卡片时，
we're gonna say card chosen
我们会说选择了卡
but they're also going to flip over.
但它们也将翻转过来。
So let's try the ghost.
因此，让我们尝试一下。
The ghost, I'm clicking on it, it's flipping both ways.
幽灵，我点击它，它正在双向翻转。
How 'bout this guy and this guy and this guy.
这个家伙和这个家伙还有这个家伙怎么样。
All right.
好吧。
So what's happening here is we are clicking on these,
所以这里发生的是我们点击这些，
it's doing this onTapGesture.
它是在onTapGesture上完成的。
It's expressing this Intent in the ViewModel.
它在ViewModel中表达了这个Intent。
The ViewModel is then asking the Model
然后，ViewModel询问模型
to go ahead and do it.
去做吧。
The Model is doing this mutating thing.
模型正在做这种变异的事情。
Once it's done this mutating thing,
一旦完成了这种变异的事情，
it's easy for this to notice
这很容易注意到
that this has changed and it gets published,
它已经改变并被发布，
objectWillChange.send,
objectWillChange.send，
and this guy observes those objectWillChange.send
这个家伙观察到那些objectWillChange.send
and is redrawing.
并正在重画。
That is the slides that I showed you,
那是我给你看的幻灯片，
the back and forth, that's what it looks like in code.
来回，这就是代码中的样子。
So we need to jump back into the slides right now
所以我们现在需要跳回幻灯片
and talk a little bit about protocols.
再谈一些协议。
A protocol is gonna look to you
一个协议会期待你
like it's a stripped-down class or struct,
就像是精简的类或结构，
stripped down because it has functions and vars
剥离下来，因为它具有函数和变量
but no implementation.
但没有实施。
So here's a protocol, moveable, that I've made up.
这是我制定的可移动协议。
It has one function and two vars.
它具有一个功能和两个变量。
One of the vars is read only there hasMoved.
var之一仅在hasMoved处读取。
You can see it has that curly brace get there.
您可以看到它带有大括号。
And then distanceFromStart is actually readable
然后distanceFromStart实际上是可读的
and writeable, that's why it has get and set.
和可写的，这就是为什么它必须得到设置。
But there's no implementation here.
但是这里没有实现。
Even those curly braces there,
甚至那里的那些花括号，
that's just saying whether those vars are read only
那只是说这些变量是否是只读的
or not, that's all there is.
还是没有，仅此而已。
Once you have a protocol declared,
声明协议后，
now any type, struct or class,
现在任何类型，结构或类
can come along and say,
可以说
yes, I'm gonna implement that.
是的，我要实现这一目标。
That's claiming to implement the protocol.
声称要实现该协议。
So here I have a struct,
所以我这里有一个结构
portable thing and it says colon Moveable
便携式的东西，它说冒号可移动
in this declaration.
在此声明中。
And when it says that,
当它说的时候，
that immediately means I sign up to implement this
立即意味着我注册实施
and therefore it must implement every var
因此，它必须实现每个var
and every function in Moveable.
以及Moveable中的每个功能。
Now we've seen this before View,
现在我们已经在View之前看到了
we have our ContentView, colon View.
我们有ContentView，冒号视图。
It signs up to be a View and that's why
它签约成为View，这就是为什么
it has to do var body,
它必须做变体，
same thing Card was, Identifiable.
卡是一样的东西，可识别。
It signed up to implement Identifiable.
它签署了实施Identifiable的协议。
It had to implement that var id.
它必须实现该var id。
Now it's also possible to have one protocol say
现在也可以说一个协议
that it requires another protocol.
它需要另一个协议。
This is called protocol inheritance,
这称为协议继承，
don't get confused with class inheritance
不要与类继承混淆
'cause we're just talking about protocols here.
因为我们在这里只是在谈论协议。
So here I have a protocol Vehicle
所以这里我有一个协议载具
and it's inheriting from Moveable.
它是从Moveable继承的。
It adds its own var there, passengerCount.
它在那里添加了自己的var，passengerCount。
So if a class like car comes along at the bottom here
因此，如果像汽车这样的课程出现在底部
and it says, I signed up to your vehicle,
它说，我签署了您的车辆，
well now it has to implement all three things from Moveable
现在它必须实现Moveable的所有三件事
and it has to implement the thing from Vehicle.
而且必须从Vehicle实施
You can also, if you're a struct or a class,
如果您是结构或类，也可以
claim to implement multiple protocols.
声称实现多种协议。
So here I have the class car.
所以这里有上课车。
It's not only saying that it's a vehicle
不只是说这是一辆车
but also that it's Impoundable and Leaseable
而且它是可移植的
and now cars can have to implement all the functions
现在汽车必须实现所有功能
in vars in all three of these protocols.
在所有这三个协议的vars中。
Now a protocol is a type.
现在，协议就是一种类型。
That means that most protocols can be used
这意味着可以使用大多数协议
in most circumstances where you have a type.
在大多数情况下，您有类型。
For example, I can have a variable m of type Moveable.
例如，我可以有一个类型为Moveable的变量m。
That's the type of m, it's a type Moveable.
那是m的类型，这是Moveable的类型。
And what does that mean?
那是什么意思呢？
Well, if I had another couple of vars,
好吧，如果我还有另外两个变量，
like car and portable,
像汽车和便携式
which are of type Car and type PortableThing,
分别是Car类型和PortableThing类型，
then I can say, m equals car or m equals portable.
那么我可以说，m等于汽车或m等于便携式。
Why can I say that?
我怎么这么说
Because car is a Moveable,
因为汽车是动车，
it implements the Moveable protocol.
它实现了可移动协议。
In fact, car implements Vehicle,
实际上，汽车实现了Vehicle
Vehicle inherits Moveable,
车辆继承了可动
and so therefore car is Moveable.
因此汽车是可移动的。
And this is great 'cause now I have this variable m,
太好了，因为现在有了这个变量m
I can start sending it functions like has moved,
我可以开始发送它的功能，例如移动，
has moved because I know that m is a Moveable.
已经移动，因为我知道m是可移动的。
And whether it's a Car in there or PortableThing,
不管是那里的汽车还是PortableThing，
we know that those vars and functions
我们知道那些变量和函数
are gonna be implemented
将被实施
because you're required to implement them
因为您需要实施它们
if you say you're one of those things.
如果你说你是其中之一。
But one thing to be a little careful of here,
但是要注意一点，
you cannot say portable equals car.
你不能说便携式等于汽车。
The var portable up there is not of type Moveable,
那里的var便携式设备不是Moveable类型，
it's of type PortableThing, different.
它是PortableThing类型，不同。
And so a Car is not a PortableThing.
因此，汽车不是PortablePorting。
They're both Moveables,
它们都是可移动的
but a Car is a different type than a PortableThing.
但是汽车的类型不同于PortableThing。
I think a Car was a class,
我认为汽车是一门课，
PortableThing was a struct.
PortableThing是一个结构。
So not even the same kind of thing.
因此，甚至没有同样的事情。
So you cannot say that.
所以你不能这么说。
While I can say m equals each of those things,
我可以说m等于所有这些东西，
I can't say they equal each other
我不能说他们彼此平等
'cause Swift is enforcing the type of the var,
因为Swift正在执行var的类型，
and then when I say portable equals,
然后当我说便携式等于
the type of the var is PortableThing,
变量的类型是PortableThing，
not type Moveable there.
不要在此处输入“可移动”。
One way to think about protocols,
一种考虑协议的方式，
and I've already mentioned this in the demo,
我已经在演示中提到了这一点，
is constrains and gains.
是制约和收获。
I use this because it rhymes,
我用这个是因为它押韵
so hopefully easy to remember,
希望很容易记住，
and it works like this.
它是这样的。
So I have this struct right here,
所以我这里有这个结构
Tesla, and it's a Vehicle,
特斯拉，它是一辆汽车，
so it implements all of those things.
因此它实现了所有这些东西。
In fact, it's constrained to implement all the things
实际上，限制所有事情的实现
in Vehicle which includes all the things in Moveable,
载具中的所有事物，
but being constrained on that is going to make it gain,
但是受到限制会使其获益，
all the things the world offers to a Vehicle.
世界为车辆提供的所有东西。
Now, you might be saying, well, wait a second here,
现在，您可能会说，嗯，在这里稍等片刻，
Vehicle is a protocol, has no implementation.
车辆是协议，没有实现。
How are we possibly gonna gain anything here?
我们怎么可能在这里获得任何收益？
It seems like I got all constrains here and I got no gains.
似乎我在这里遇到了所有限制，但没有收获。
Well, the magic is in the keyword extension.
好吧，关键在于关键字扩展。
In Swift, we can extend protocols to have implementation.
在Swift中，我们可以扩展协议以实现。
and we just say extension, name of the protocol,
我们只说扩展名，协议名称，
and then we can put functions with implementation,
然后我们可以将功能和实现放在一起
functions in vars with implementation.
vars中的函数及其实现。
Now we can't have any vars that have storage here.
现在我们不能在这里存储任何变量了。
So there is that restriction,
所以有这个限制
it has to be computed vars,
它必须是计算变量
like var body was computed,
就像var body是计算出来的一样
remember, it had the curly braces,
记住，它有花括号，
have to do the same thing here,
必须在这里做同样的事情
but we can add as many things as we want.
但是我们可以添加任意数量的东西。
With this extension of Vehicle registerWithDMV,
随着车辆登记簿的扩展，DMV
now Teslas and all other Vehicles
现在是特斯拉和所有其他车辆
can be registered with DMV.
可以在DMV中注册。
In other words, they gained that ability
换句话说，他们获得了这种能力
by living with the constraint that they have had
忍受他们所受的束缚
to implement those methods and vars
实现那些方法和变量
that were in those protocols.
在那些协议中。
So, yeah, this is really the center
是的，这真的是中心
of functional programming in Swift.
Swift中的函数式编程。
And the protocol View is probably
协议视图可能是
the poster child for doing this.
这样做的发帖者。
And we're gonna see more about View
我们将看到更多关于View的信息
in a couple of slides here.
在这里有几张幻灯片。
In addition to adding functions,
除了添加功能之外，
like registerWithDMV, you can also use an extension
像registerWithDMV一样，您也可以使用扩展名
to protocol if you want to add default implementations.
如果要添加默认实现，请选择协议。
So here I am extending Moveable
所以我在这里扩展Moveable
and I'm actually providing a default implementation
我实际上提供了一个默认实现
for hasMoved as hasMoved
为hasMoved作为hasMoved
is one of the vars in the protocol
是协议中的变量之一
but I'm providing a default implementation here.
但是我在这里提供了默认的实现。
I'm just looking at my distance from start,
我只是在看我的距离
and if that's greater than zero,
如果大于零，
I'm gonna assume I've moved.
我假设我已经搬家了。
And I'm doing this with an extension to Moveable.
而我正在通过对Moveable进行扩展。
So this makes it possible for me then to have a struct,
因此，这使我有可能拥有一个结构，
I have one here called ChessPiece which is a Moveable,
我这里有一个叫ChessPiece的棋子，它是可移动的，
you can move chess pieces.
您可以移动棋子。
ChessPiece does not need to implement hasMoved.
ChessPiece不需要实现hasMoved。
If ChessPiece just implements moveBy and distanceFromStart,
如果ChessPiece仅实现moveBy和distanceFromStart，
then it will have successfully implemented Moveable
那么它将成功实现Moveable
because it'll pick up the default implementation
因为它将采用默认实现
from that extension right there.
从那扩展名那里。
Now, if ChessPiece wanted to implement hasMoved itself,
现在，如果ChessPiece想要自己实现hasMoved，
it could, but it doesn't have to
可以，但是不必
because there's a default implementation
因为有一个默认的实现
for hasMoved in that extension.
对于该扩展中的hasMoved。
Now, you can use extensions of course,
现在，您当然可以使用扩展程序了，
to add code to structs and classes as well,
还要向结构和类中添加代码，
not just protocols.
不只是协议。
So here, for example, I have a struct called Boat
例如，在这里，我有一个名为Boat的结构
and it's got its own methods,
它有自己的方法，
whatever they might be.
无论他们是什么。
And here I'm adding extension to Boat,
在这里，我将扩展添加到Boat中，
a function sailAroundTheWorld.
一个功能sailAroundTheWorld。
And this extension, you can see, has curly braces,
您可以看到，该扩展名带有花括号，
it has an implementation.
它有一个实现。
This is an actual implementation of sailAroundTheWorld
这是sailAroundTheWorld的实际实现
that we've added to Boat.
我们已经添加到Boat中
You can even make something like a Boat conformed
您甚至可以制作类似Boat的产品
to a protocol purely by using your extension.
完全通过使用您的扩展名来访问协议。
So Boat doesn't implement any protocols right now
所以Boat现在不执行任何协议
but I can make Boat implement Moveable
但我可以使Boat工具可移动
by having the extension to Boat that says colon Moveable
通过扩展到表示结肠可移动的Boat
and then in that extension,
然后在那个扩展中，
implement moveBy and distanceFromStart.
实现moveBy和distanceFromStart。
Now Boat is a Moveable.
现在船是可移动的。
And I added it totally with extension.
我将其全部添加为扩展名。
It's not an uncommon thing to do
这不是一件罕见的事
to take a structure or class and make it conformed
采取结构或类别并使其符合标准
to a protocol using purely an extension,
纯粹使用扩展的协议
or you add the code in an extension.
或者您将代码添加到扩展程序中。
Why do we do all this protocol stuff?
为什么我们要做所有这些协议呢？
Now, for those of you who are coming
现在，对于那些即将到来的人
from object oriented programming, this was gonna seem like,
从面向对象的程序设计来看，
what's going on here?
这里发生了什么？
Why do we do this?
我们为什么要做这个？
Well, there's a really good conceptual reason
嗯，有一个非常好的概念上的原因
why we're doing this.
为什么我们要这样做。
Protocols are a way for types, structs and classes,
协议是一种用于类型，结构和类的方式，
other protocols, even enums,
其他协议，甚至枚举，
which we haven't talked about,
我们没有谈论过，
to say what they are capable of,
说出他们的能力，
what functions they can do, what vars they have on them,
他们可以做什么功能，他们有什么变量，
and it's also a way for other code
这也是其他代码的一种方式
to demand certain behavior from other objects
要求其他物体的某些行为
by demanding that they conform to a protocol,
通过要求他们遵守协议，
either by having a variable of that type
通过具有该类型的变量
that they're trying to assign
他们正在尝试分配
or parameter to a function.
或函数的参数。
And there's even other mechanisms you're gonna see
甚至还有其他机制
soon when we talk about generics and protocols
不久，当我们谈论泛型和协议时
for demanding that you want that thing to be a Moveable.
要求您希望该东西是可移动的。
It has to be a Vehicle, whatever.
无论如何，它必须是一辆载具。
You can demand it now that you have this protocol.
现在，有了此协议，就可以要求它了。
But in all of that, neither side has to reveal
但在所有这些方面，双方都不必透露
what sort of structure class you are.
您是哪种结构类。
You completely can be anything you want.
您完全可以随心所欲。
You just say you implement Moveable
你只是说你实现了Moveable
and now you can be operated on as a Moveable,
现在您可以将其作为可移动设备进行操作，
but you could be anything.
但你可以是任何人。
You could be a Car,
你可能是汽车
you could be a PortableThing.
您可能是PortableThing。
You could be a Boat.
你可能是一条船。
We know when neither side cares.
我们知道什么时候双方都不在乎。
All one side cares is that you can do the Moveable things
一方面，您可以做可移动的事情
and all the other side cares is that it
而所有其他副作用是
implement all those Moveable things.
实现所有这些可移动的东西。
So this is what functional programming,
这就是函数式编程
or really we might call it,
或实际上我们可以称之为
protocol-oriented programming, is all about.
面向协议的编程就是这样。
It's about formalizing how data structures
这是关于规范数据结构的方式
in our application function, how they behaved.
在我们的应用程序功能中，它们的行为方式。
Even when we talk about vars in the context of protocols,
即使我们在协议的上下文中谈论var，
we don't define how they're stored or computed,
我们没有定义它们的存储或计算方式，
we don't even say where
我们甚至不说它们的存储或计算位置，
we just talk about whether they're read only or read, write.
我们只是在谈论它们是只读还是读，写。
And through all this we focus on the functionality.
通过所有这些，我们专注于功能。
We're hiding the implementation details.
我们隐藏了实现细节。
It's kind of the ultimate promise of encapsulation
这是封装的最终希望
from object-oriented programming
来自面向对象的编程
but it's really taken to a higher level
但这确实是一个更高的层次
because it doesn't mix it inexorably
因为它不会无情地混合它
with the data and all that,
有了数据和所有这些，
it's just talking about the functionality.
只是在谈论功能。
And all of this gets even more powerful
所有这些都变得更加强大
when we combine it with generics.
当我们将其与泛型结合使用时。
Protocols plus generics equals,
协议加上泛型等于
as I say here, super powers.
正如我在这里所说的，超级大国。
So let's look at how generics,
让我们来看看泛型
remember that's the don't care stuff
记住那是无关紧要的东西
that we talked about last time,
我们上次谈到的
how it combines with protocols to make super powers.
它如何与协议结合以产生超能力。
Here we go.
开始了。
Let's do this by example.
让我们以示例方式进行操作。
Let's say I had a protocol called Greatness,
假设我有一个名为Greatness的协议，
and this protocol only has one function in it
这个协议里面只有一个功能
which is, isGreaterThan other.
就是比其他大。
One argument other to this function isGreaterThan.
此函数的另一个参数是GreaterThan。
By the way, this is kind of an interesting function
顺便说一句，这是一个有趣的功能
because the type of other is capital S Self.
因为其他类型是大写S Self。
That's a special kind of name of a type in a protocol
这是协议中一种特殊的类型名称
which means the actual type
表示实际类型
that's implementing this protocol,
正在实施该协议，
because remember, protocols themselves
因为请记住，协议本身
have no implementation,
没有执行，
they get implemented by structs and classes.
它们通过结构和类实现。
So that Self means that the actual structure class
因此，Self表示实际的结构类
that implements this,
实现这一点，
that is executing it at the time.
当时正在执行它。
So that's kind of cool.
所以这很酷。
And I'm gonna show you how that works
我要告诉你它是如何工作的
in just a few clicks here.
只需点击几下。
So if we have this protocol, look at what we can do.
因此，如果我们有此协议，请看我们能做什么。
extension Array, so I'm adding something to Array,
扩展数组，所以我要添加一些东西到数组，
where the Element,
元素在哪里
the don't care of the Array,
不在乎数组
conforms to Greatness, colon Greatness.
符合伟大，冒号伟大。
So that where I put in red
这样我放在红色的地方
because it's really the key part
因为这真的是关键
of connecting generics and protocols.
泛型和协议的连接。
Here, I'm actually going to add a var,
在这里，我实际上要添加一个变量，
or I could do it with functions,
或者我可以通过功能来做到这一点
but I'm gonna add a var here to Array
但我要在这里向数组添加一个变量
so that every Array where the Element, the don't care,
这样每个元素不在乎的数组，
conforms to Greatness will get this var.
符合Greatness将会得到此var。
Let that sink in.
让它沉入。
Now, this var will not exist in Arrays
现在，此变量将不存在于数组中
where the don't cares don't implement
不在乎的地方
the protocol Greatness.
协议伟大。
This var just will not be there.
该变量只是不会存在。
If you tried to type it in your code,
如果您尝试在代码中键入它，
the compiler would say,
编译器会说，
oh, this Array does not implement greatest.
哦，这个Array没有实现最大的。
It would only say it implements greatest,
它只会说它实施得最好，
only lets you type that in without error
只允许您正确输入
if it was an Array of something that implements
如果它是实现的东西的数组
the protocol Greatness.
协议伟大。
Now I like to call this, we care a little bit.
现在我喜欢这样称呼，我们有点关心。
(chuckles) Right?
（笑）对吗？
Normally we call generics don't care,
通常我们称泛型不在乎，
Element is a don't care,
元素不在乎，
Array doesn't care what's inside of it.
数组不在乎其中的内容。
Well, this is kind of,
好吧，这有点
this extension to Array cares a little bit about Element.
这个对Array的扩展有点关心Element。
It doesn't really care what Element is,
真的不在乎元素是什么
can be any struct or class,
可以是任何结构或类，
but we do care that it implements Greatness.
但是我们确实关心它实现了伟大。
So this is care a little bit,
所以这有点关怀，
you wanna think of it that way.
你想那样想。
Then this var greatness,
然后这个无尽的伟大，
look what its type is, Element.
看看它的类型是Element。
It's the don't care 'cause I'm gonna look through the Array
这是因为我要遍历数组
and find the one that's the greatest by calling
并通过致电找到最伟大的
isGreaterThan other on all of the things
在所有事情上都比其他伟大
in the Array which I know I can do
在我知道我可以做的数组中
because this extension to Array
因为这个对Array的扩展
is only where the Elements implement Greatness.
只有元素实现伟大的地方。
See how it all works here?
在这里看到一切如何？
So you can easily imagine,
因此，您可以轻松想象，
I'm not gonna show the code here,
我不会在这里显示代码，
but you can easily imagine building a for loop
但您可以轻松想象构建一个for循环
that just goes through all the Elements,
只是贯穿所有元素，
calls isGreaterThan on all of them,
通话比所有通话都好，
figures out which one is the greatest
找出哪一个是最大的
and then just returns it.
然后将其返回。
Some of you are looking at all this,
你们当中有些人正在看这一切，
and I'm sure you're shivering, as I say here.
就像我在这里所说的，我确定您正在发抖。
You gotta be thinking, holy cow,
你必须要思考，圣牛，
how am I supposed to be expected to know
我应该怎么知道
how to design my code using this technology?
如何使用这项技术设计代码？
I mean, this is just all new to me.
我的意思是，这对我来说是全新的。
And this is indeed a very powerful foundation
这确实是一个非常强大的基础
for designing things, very powerful.
对于设计事物，非常强大。
But functional programming does require
但是函数式编程确实需要
some mastery that only comes with experience.
一些只有经验才能掌握的技巧。
And the good news is that you can do
好消息是你可以做
a lot of stuff in SwiftUI, most things,
SwiftUI中的很多东西，大多数事情，
without really mastering functional programming.
无需真正掌握功能编程。
But here you are at Stanford trying to get a good education.
但是在这里，您正在斯坦福大学努力接受良好的教育。
And so the reason I'm explaining this to you now
所以我现在向你解释的原因
is so that the more you use it in SwiftUI,
以便您在SwiftUI中使用它的次数增加，
the more you see it in the documentation
您在文档中看到的越多
where you see these wares happening,
在这些商品发生的地方，
we see protocols like View
我们看到像View这样的协议
and Identifiable coming down the road,
并且可以确定的是，
that you're not just saying,
你不只是在说，
I have to put colon View here,
我必须在这里放冒号
you're actually understanding
你实际上是在理解
how it's being designed underneath.
它是如何设计的。
And the more you see it, the more it's gonna sink in,
而且您看到的越多，它就会越陷进去，
and the more eventually you might start to be capable
最终您可能会开始变得更有能力
of doing functional programming design as well.
同时进行功能编程设计。
But no one expects you, right now,
但是现在没有人期望你
to be able to be designing stuff
能够设计东西
where you're adding extensions to protocols with generics
在其中使用泛型向协议添加扩展
and all that.
等等。
But eventually you'll be able to.
但是最终您将能够。
And in the meantime you'll kind of know
同时，您会知道
what's going on in SwiftUI.
SwiftUI中发生了什么。
So I'm just putting this one slide up here about enum,
所以我只是把这张幻灯片放在这里，关于枚举，
but once again, not gonna talk about enum in this lecture.
但是再一次，在本讲座中，我们将不再讨论枚举。
We'll talk about it soon, not to worry.
我们会尽快谈论，不用担心。
So that pretty much covers
因此，几乎涵盖
what we're going to talk about today on architecture
今天我们要谈论的建筑
and we're almost there in covering this entire topic.
我们几乎涵盖了整个主题。
And now I'm gonna shift gears entirely
现在我要完全换档
and go to a completely different topic
然后去一个完全不同的话题
which is layout, in other words,
换句话说，就是布局
how do we decide where all our Views go on screen?
我们如何确定所有视图在屏幕上的位置？
The way that SwiftUI does this is amazingly simple.
SwiftUI做到这一点的方法非常简单。
It's one of the more elegant things in all of SwiftUI.
这是所有SwiftUI中最精美的东西之一。
There's really only three steps to doing this.
确实只有三个步骤。
The first one is the Container Views,
第一个是容器视图，
like HStacks and VStacks and things like that.
例如HStacks和VStacks之类的东西。
They offer space to the Views that are inside of them.
它们为其中的视图提供了空间。
And then those Views choose a size for themselves,
然后，这些视图自行选择尺寸，
what they want to be.
他们想要成为什么。
Based on that offer,
根据该报价，
they could choose a size same as the offer,
他们可以选择与报价相同的尺寸，
that's the most common,
这是最常见的
they can choose a size smaller than the offer,
他们可以选择比报价要小的尺寸，
they could choose a size that's larger even than the offer.
他们可以选择比报价更大的尺寸。
So they use, in a very kind of good encapsulation way,
因此，它们以一种很好的封装方式使用
Views decide what size they're going to be.
视图决定了它们的大小。
No one tells them what size to be.
没有人告诉他们要多大。
We just offer them space, they decide.
他们决定，我们只是为他们提供空间。
But then after that, the Container Views like the stacks,
但是之后，容器视图就像堆栈一样，
it's their job to position their Views inside of themselves.
将视图放置在自己的内部是他们的工作。
And that's it, these are the three steps
就是这样，这是三个步骤
to get everything laid out in SwiftUI.
以便将所有内容布置在SwiftUI中。
So let's dive into this a little bit.
因此，让我们深入了解一下。
Let's talk about Container Views.
让我们谈谈容器视图。
So the most common Container View
所以最常见的容器视图
that you're already familiar with is HStack and VStack.
您已经熟悉的是HStack和VStack。
Of course, there's ZStack as well
当然，还有ZStack
that kind of stacks them on top of each other,
这种堆叠在一起
but HStack and VStack are interesting
但是HStack和VStack很有趣
in that they divide up the space that's offered to them
因为他们将提供给他们的空间分开了
amongst all of their subviews.
在所有子视图中
And we'll talk about how that works in a moment.
稍后我们将讨论其工作原理。
ForEach is kind of an unusual Container View.
ForEach是一种不寻常的容器视图。
It actually defers the positioning
它实际上推迟了定位
and sizing to the container that it's in,
并调整其所在容器的尺寸，
that's why we put our CardViews that were in
这就是为什么我们将我们的CardViews
that ForEach into an HStack.
将ForEach放入HStack。
So their ForEach is deferring letting the HStack decide.
因此，他们的ForEach正在推迟让HStack做出决定。
And a hidden thing that's going on with layout is modifiers,
布局中隐藏着的一件事是修饰符，
like .padding and others.
例如.padding等。
They essentially contain the View that they modify,
它们本质上包含它们修改的视图，
if you wanna think of it that way,
如果你想这样想，
and some of them, like padding, do layout.
其中一些元素（例如填充）进行布局。
So let's talk a little bit more
所以我们再谈一点
in detail about HStack and VStack,
有关HStack和VStack的详细信息，
the most important one or at least the one
最重要的一项或至少一项
that's doing the most layout.
布局最多。
The way that the stacks divide up the space
堆栈划分空间的方式
that they're offered is kind of divided equally
提供给他们的情况是平均分配的
and then they offer it to the least flexible Views first.
然后他们首先将其提供给最不灵活的视图。
So what do we mean by that?
那么，那是什么意思呢？
So an example of a very space inflexible View is Image.
因此，非常灵活的视图就是图像。
So we haven't talked about image yet
所以我们还没有谈论图像
but it's just a View that shows an image,
但这只是一个显示图像的视图，
as you might imagine.
如您所想。
And of course it wants to be the size of that image,
当然，它希望是图像的大小，
pretty inflexible in that way.
那种方式很不灵活。
So generally the Images
所以一般来说图片
are gonna get the space they want first.
首先要获得他们想要的空间。
Another example of a pretty inflexible View,
另一个僵化的View的另一个例子，
not quite as inflexible as Image is Text.
不像图像是文字那样僵硬。
Text always wants to size itself
文字总是想自行调整大小
to fit the text inside of it, understandably,
可以理解其中的文字，这是可以理解的，
but it does have a way to be a little bit smaller
但是它确实可以缩小一点
and put dot dot dot at the end of the text
并在文本末尾加点号
as we'll talk about in a second here.
正如我们稍后将在这里讨论的那样。
So it's not quite as inflexible as an Image.
因此，它不像图像那么灵活。
And most Views are very flexible.
而且大多数视图都非常灵活。
For example, all the Shapes,
例如，所有形状
like RoundedRectangle that we saw,
就像我们看到的RoundedRectangle
whatever size you offer it,
无论您提供什么尺寸，
it's pretty much gonna take that
这几乎可以接受
and it's going to draw itself appropriately in that size.
并且它将以该大小适当地绘制自身。
So after one of these Views chooses its own size
因此，在其中一种视图选择了自己的尺寸之后
and takes whatever size it wants,
并采用所需的尺寸，
that size is removed from the space that the stack
从堆栈的空间中删除了该大小
is trying to allocate,
试图分配，
and then it goes on to the next least flexible Views
然后进入下一个最不灵活的视图
and rinse and repeat until all the space is used up.
冲洗并重复直到所有空间用完。
So it's as simple as that.
就是这么简单。
That's how HStack and VStack apportion their space.
这就是HStack和VStack分配其空间的方式。
Now, after all the Views
现在，毕竟
have chosen their size then the HStack
选择了他们的大小然后HStack
and VStack sizes itself to fit those Views
而VStack的大小可以适应这些视图
with whatever little spacing in between that it provides.
两者之间的间距很小。
HStack and VStack work with any View,
HStack和VStack可与任何View一起使用，
of course, but there's a couple of them
当然，但是有几个
that I'm gonna introduce to you here
我要在这里介绍给你
that really help with layout.
确实有助于布局。
One of them is called Spacer.
其中之一称为垫片。
So a Spacer is just a View
因此，垫片只是一个视图
that takes all of the space that's offered to it.
占用了它提供的所有空间。
So if you give it space, it's gonna use that space.
因此，如果您给它空间，它将使用该空间。
And so it's used for filling in space.
因此，它用于填充空间。
Now it doesn't actually draw anything,
现在它实际上并没有画任何东西，
it just kind of uses up space in an HStack
它只是在占用HStack中的空间
or VStack, that's why it's called a Spacer.
或VStack，这就是为什么它被称为Spacer。
It has that minLength argument which is the minimum size
它具有最小长度的minLength参数
that it should be in the direction
它应该朝着方向
we're laying out horizontally or vertically,
我们是水平或垂直布置
depending on whether it's HStack or VStack,
取决于是HStack还是VStack，
although we usually don't specify
尽管我们通常不指定
because the default for that is the right amount
因为默认值是正确的金额
of space on this platform.
在这个平台上的空间。
One thing that you're gonna start
你要开始的一件事
to get used to as the quarter goes on,
习惯了本季度的发展，
that even though we're focusing on iOS,
即使我们专注于iOS，
you can use SwiftUI on Apple Watch and Apple TV
您可以在Apple Watch和Apple TV上使用SwiftUI
and the spacing and the layout
以及间距和布局
is a little different on these platforms.
在这些平台上有点不同。
And SwiftUI is really smart about saying,
SwiftUI真的很聪明地说：
I'm on an Apple watch so I'm gonna use this much space
我在Apple Watch上，所以我要用这么多空间
in my Spacer by default or whatever.
默认情况下在我的垫片中。
So that's why we really wanna try
这就是为什么我们要尝试
and use these default,
并使用这些默认值
and not specify minLength when we use Spacer.
并且在使用Spacer时不指定minLength。
Same thing with spacing on the HStack itself,
HStack本身也有间距
HStack spacing, we don't wanna do that.
HStack间距，我们不想这样做。
Even padding, generally it's fine to put padding
即使是填充，通常也可以放置填充
but if you start putting numbers in there
但是如果你开始把数字放在那里
and specifying exact paddings like we saw,
并像我们看到的那样指定确切的填充，
you're defeating a little bit
你在打败一点
of the purpose of this platform independence.
此平台独立性的目的。
Now, sometimes you need it,
现在，有时您需要它，
you just do but we try to use these defaults
您可以，但是我们尝试使用这些默认值
as much as possible.
越多越好。
So another cool View to put in
因此，要添加另一个很酷的视图
an HStack or VStack is Divider.
HStack或VStack是Divider。
So Divider just draws a dividing line,
所以分频器只是画一条分界线，
again, platform specific,
同样，特定于平台
it depends what a divider looks like
这取决于分隔线的外观
in the context that it's in.
在它的上下文中。
Of course, the Divider is not like a Spacer,
当然，分频器不像垫片
it doesn't use all up all that space.
它不会占用所有的空间。
It only uses enough space to draw that line.
它仅使用足够的空间来绘制该线。
And the line obviously goes opposite to the direction
而且该线显然与方向相反
that we're laying out.
我们正在布局。
So for an HStack,
因此，对于HStack，
the divider is obviously gonna be a vertical line,
分隔线显然将是一条垂直线，
and for a VStack, it's gonna be a horizontal line.
对于VStack，它将是一条水平线。
So you're almost certainly gonna want to use one
所以您几乎肯定会想要使用一个
or both of these in your next homework assignment.
或在下一个作业中同时使用这两种方法。
And they're really valuable for doing layout with stacks.
它们对于使用堆栈进行布局真的很有价值。
These HStacks and VStacks,
这些HStack和VStack，
I told you that they're kind of choosing
我告诉过你他们是有选择的
which of its Views to offer space to next priority wise
它的哪些观点为下一个优先领域提供了空间
using this least flexible thing,
用这个最不灵活的东西，
but you can actually override that
但实际上您可以覆盖
with this View modifier layoutPriority.
使用此视图修改器layoutPriority。
So here's an example of an HStack
这是一个HStack的例子
that has a Text that's really important.
它的文本非常重要。
It's got an Image which we know is very not flexible,
它有一张我们知道非常不灵活的图片，
and so normally would get a lot of attention from HStack.
因此通常会引起HStack的关注。
And then it has another Text which is less important.
然后有另一个不那么重要的文本。
So I've added the View modifier dot layoutPriority 100
所以我添加了View修饰符点layoutPriority 100
which I can pick any number I want there really,
我可以选择任何我真正想要的号码，
it doesn't matter, it's a floating point number.
没关系，这是一个浮点数。
And that's more than the default layoutPriority
这不仅仅是默认的layoutPriority
which is zero.
这是零。
So when this HStack goes to offer its space,
因此，当该HStack提供其空间时，
it's going to offer this Text space first.
它将首先提供此文本空间。
And that Text is gonna say,
那文本会说，
well, sure, I wanna be this big
好吧，当然，我想变得这么大
so I can fit this word, important, all the way.
所以我可以很重要地一直使用这个词
Then it's gonna say, okay,
那会说，好吧，
well there's no other high priority ones.
好吧，没有其他高优先级的产品了。
There could be other ones with different numbers.
可能还有其他号码不同的号码。
It starts with the highest priority and goes down.
它以最高优先级开始，然后下降。
And so now it goes to do the Image
所以现在去做图像
because that's less flexible than the Text,
因为它不如文本灵活，
Image gets it space and then the unimportant text
图像得到空间，然后是不重要的文本
has to fit itself into the space remaining.
必须适应剩余的空间。
And as we mentioned before,
正如我们之前提到的
when a Text doesn't get enough space,
当文本没有足够的空间时，
it will put dot dot dot in there to elide
它会在其中放点
or shorten the text to fit the space it did get.
或缩短文字以适合其实际空间。
It always wants to be its space.
它一直想成为它的空间。
It never wants to be larger than its text fits in.
它从不希望超出其文本的大小。
It always wants to be the exact size
它总是想要确切的尺寸
but if it's forced to be smaller,
但是如果被迫变小，
it knows how to do dot dot dot.
它知道如何做点点。
Another and significant part of HStack and VStack's layout
HStack和VStack布局的另一个重要部分
is their alignment.
是他们的一致。
So imagine you have a VStack, a vertical stack of Views.
因此，假设您有一个VStack，即垂直的View堆栈。
And what if those Views pick their own size
如果这些视图自行选择大小
and they're not the same width.
它们的宽度不一样。
So they can't all be kind of filling
所以他们不可能都充满
the whole width of this vertical stack.
此垂直堆栈的整个宽度。
So does the VStack left align them
VStack也会左对齐吗
or center them or right align them?
或将它们居中或使其对齐？
How does it know where to put them?
它怎么知道将它们放在哪里？
Well, there's actually an argument to VStack and HStack.
好吧，实际上有一个关于VStack和HStack的争论。
We already know that VStack and HStack
我们已经知道VStack和HStack
have the argument spacing which determines
具有确定参数的参数间距
the spacing between the Views.
视图之间的间距。
It also has another argument, alignment.
它还有另一个论点，对齐。
And alignment takes an alignment guide as its argument.
对齐方式以对齐方式为准。
And one of the alignment guides, for example, is leading.
例如，其中一个对齐向导处于领先地位。
Now, why leading here instead of left?
现在，为什么要领导这里而不是离开？
If I just want this Vstack
如果我只想要这个Vstack
to have all of these be left aligned,
使所有这些保持对齐，
why don't I say dot left?
我为什么不说左点？
And in fact, there's no such thing as dot left.
实际上，不存在像点这样的东西。
And .leading means to have the things
.lead意味着拥有事物
in the VStack line up
在VStack阵容中
so that their edges start from where text comes from.
这样它们的边缘就从文本的来源开始。
In different languages sometimes
有时用不同的语言
the text comes from the right and moves to the left,
文字从右边移到左边，
like Hebrew and Arabic.
像希伯来语和阿拉伯语。
So we want our VStacks to generally match up
因此，我们希望我们的VStack一般能够匹配
with that text coming from that side.
文字来自那一边。
Text baselines can also be lined up.
文本基线也可以排列。
So HStacks, well, it only makes sense in an HStack.
因此，HStacks，仅在HStack中才有意义。
You can line it up so that the bottom of the text,
您可以将其对齐，以使文本的底部，
even if they're different fonts,
即使它们是不同的字体，
will all be lined up in your HStack.
将全部排在您的HStack中。
You can even define your own things
您甚至可以定义自己的东西
to line up alignment guides.
对齐对齐指南。
And that's a little beyond the scope of this course.
这超出了本课程的范围。
So we're just gonna use the built in ones,
所以我们只是要使用内置的
like .center which is usually the default alignment
像.center通常是默认对齐方式
is to center the thing in the middle
就是把东西放在中间
of the VStack or the HStack.
VStack或HStack。
But there's also top and bottom trailing
但也有顶部和底部的尾随
leading all these things.
领导所有这些事情。
As you can imagine, when you just start typing in an Xcode,
可以想象，当您开始输入Xcode时，
VStack alignment colon, of course, Xcode will help you
VStack对齐冒号，当然，Xcode将为您提供帮助
and tell you what all those built-ins are.
并告诉您所有这些内置功能。
That's it for stacks.
堆栈就是这样。
Stacks are very important.
堆栈非常重要。
But there's this other thing, modifiers, like .padding,
但是还有另一件事，修饰符，例如.padding，
that I said kind of act like essentially Container Views.
我说过的行为本质上就像是容器视图。
Remember that these things,
记住这些东西，
.padding, et cetera, they return a View.
.padding等，它们返回一个View。
And you might've thought they just return a View
您可能以为他们只是返回一个View
so that we could then send them another,
这样我们就可以再寄给他们
call another function on them,
在它们上调用另一个函数，
.foregroundColor and then that gives us a View back,
.foregroundColor然后返回给我们一个View
we call .padding on that.
我们称其为.padding。
And that gives us a View back and call.font on that.
这为我们提供了View并在其上调用.font。
So it's not just to give us a View back
因此，不只是给我们一个“视图”
so we can call another function on it.
因此我们可以在其上调用另一个函数。
Those Views that come back
那些回来的观点
might actually be participating in the layout.
可能实际上正在参与布局。
Now, most of them don't participate,
现在，大多数人不参加，
like font and foregroundColor.
像font和foregroundColor。
They're not affecting layout
它们不影响布局
so any space they're offered by an Hstack
因此Hstack提供的任何空间
or some other container,
或其他一些容器，
they're just gonna pass it on to whatever View they contain.
他们只是将其传递给包含的任何视图。
For the purposes of this slide,
在本幻灯片中，
we're gonna think of a View
我们会想到一个视图
that these modifiers modify as being contained by that View
这些修饰符修改为包含在该视图中
that the modifier returns which it kind of is.
修饰符返回的是哪种。
We're gonna see how these View modifiers
我们将看看这些View修饰符
are made next week, probably, or the week after,
是在下周或下周制作的
depending on how things go.
视情况而定。
And you'll see that kind of really what's happening
而且您会真正看到这种情况
is that it's containing the View it's modifying.
它包含要修改的视图。
What about these modifiers that actually participate
这些实际参与的修饰符呢？
in the layout process like padding.
在布局过程中像填充。
Let's look at padding.
让我们看一下填充。
The View that's returned by .padding, this modifier,
.padding，此修饰符，
it offers the View that it's modifying a space
它提供了它正在修改空间的视图
that's the same size as was offered to it
与提供的尺寸相同
but reduced by 10 points in this case,
但在这种情况下降低了10分，
whatever the padding is.
无论填充是什么。
It might be if that 10 is not there,
如果那10个不存在，
then it would be whatever system appropriate padding.
那么它将是任何适合系统的填充。
It's essentially removing that 10
基本上是删除那10个
because it knows it's supposed to provide the 10.
因为它知道应该提供10。
And then the View that's returned by padding
然后通过填充返回的视图
chooses its own size to be whatever size
选择自己的尺寸为任意尺寸
the thing that it's modifying ended up being plus 10.
它正在修改的东西最终是加10。
So that's what padding does,
这就是填充的作用
it adds 10 points around the outside
它在外面增加了10分
or whatever edges you say.
或您所说的任何优势。
Another thing is modifying.
另一件事是修改。
So you see how .padding modifier is just a View
因此，您将看到.padding修饰符只是一个View
that participates in the layout.
参与布局。
What's another example of this?
另一个例子是什么？
You've already used it in your homework, .aspectRatio.
您已经在作业中使用了.aspectRatio。
The View that's returned by .aspectRatio modifier,
.aspectRatio修饰符返回的View，
it takes the space offered to it
它占用了提供的空间
and it picks a size for itself
并自行选择大小
that's either smaller than that offered size
小于提供的尺寸
and has the aspect ratio,
并具有长宽比，
that's if we choose the .fit option of aspectRatio,
那就是如果我们选择AspectRatio的.fit选项，
or it could be bigger than the size that's offered to it,
或者它可能大于所提供的大小，
that's the .fill option that uses all the offered space.
这是使用所有提供的空间的.fill选项。
And so yes, it is possible when you're a View,
因此，是的，当您使用View时，
when you're offered a certain amount of space,
当您有一定的空间时，
you can choose your size to be larger.
您可以选择更大的尺寸。
Now that's rare.
现在很少见了。
We don't generally want Views kind of
我们通常不希望Views of
spilling out all over each other,
互相溢出
but it makes sense,
但这很有意义
like in this aspectRatio fill, maybe that makes sense.
像在这方面比率填充，也许这是有道理的。
So then the aspectRatio View that's now sized itself
因此，现在调整自身大小的AspectRatio视图
to have that aspect ratio,
具有该长宽比，
offers the space that it chose
提供选择的空间
to whatever View it's modifying, like our CardView.
修改它的任何视图，例如CardView。
So our CardView fits itself then
这样我们的CardView就适合自己了
in that nice aspect ratio space.
在那个不错的宽高比空间中。
So let's see an example of a full layout happening
所以让我们看一个完整布局的例子
in the size being passed around and things like that.
在传递的大小之类的东西上。
So here's an HStack similar to the one
所以这是一个类似于
we have in our Memorize game,
我们在记忆游戏中
not exactly the same but very, very similar.
不完全相同，但非常非常相似。
How is the space for this thing apportioned?
这个东西的空间如何分配？
Well, the first thing to understand is that the first View
好吧，首先要了解的是
that's gonna be offered the space into
将会提供空间
which this whole green thing goes is that padding View.
这整个绿色的东西就是填充视图。
It's the outermost View.
这是最外面的视图。
It's actually the View that is this whole thing in the end
最终，实际上就是视图
but it's gonna be offered whatever space
但无论空间多大，都会有提供
is available for this whole green construct here.
可用于此处的整个绿色结构。
Now what it's going to do, it's going to reduce,
现在要做的是减少
take 10 points off the edges of it and pass that space
从其边缘取10点并通过该空间
that's left onto the next View
留给下一个视图
which is the View returned by the foregroundColor modifier.
这是前景色修改器返回的视图。
Now that modifier isn't really participating in the layout,
现在，修饰符并没有真正参与布局，
doesn't really have any effect
真的没有任何作用
on the size and position the thing,
在东西的大小和位置上，
so it just passes that on untouched to the HStack.
因此它只是将其原封不动地传递给HStack。
Now, the HStack, as we know,
现在，众所周知，HStack
is big time layout View.
是大时间布局视图。
It's going to divide up its space starting out equally
它将开始平等地划分其空间
and since the aspectRatios aren't things like Images
由于aspectRatio不是像Images这样的东西
or Texts that are fixed sizes,
或固定大小的文字，
it's going to end up dividing the space equally
最终将空间平均分配
among all of the aspectRatio Views in the ForEach,
在ForEach的所有AspectRatio视图中，
because we know the ForEach itself
因为我们知道ForEach本身
just defers to the HStack.
只是顺应HStack。
So it's the aspectRatio Views now
所以现在是aspectRatio Views
that are being laid out in HStack.
正在HStack中进行布局。
Each aspectRatio View is going to set its width
每个aspectRatio视图将设置其宽度
to be its share of the HStack's width
占HStack宽度的份额
and then pick a height that matches the aspect ratio,
然后选择与宽高比匹配的高度，
the 2/3 aspect ratio,
2/3的宽高比，
or if the height is limited here,
或者如果高度限制在这里，
it might be the other way around
可能是相反的方式
where the aspectRatio View takes
AspectRatio View需要的位置
all of the height it's offered
它提供的所有高度
and instead chooses a width that's less to fit.
而是选择不太适合的宽度。
So it could go either way.
因此，它可能以任何一种方式进行。
It depends on whichever is gonna fit best
这取决于哪个最适合
in the space that is offered.
在提供的空间中。
Then the aspectRatio has picked that size.
然后AspectRatio选择了该大小。
It's going to offer that to the CardView
它将提供给CardView
and the CardView is going to use all of the space
而CardView将使用所有空间
because it's like a normal View,
因为就像普通的视图一样
whatever space you offer it, pretty much it's going to use.
无论您提供多少空间，它几乎都会被使用。
After all this offering and sizing happens,
在所有这些提供和调整大小之后，
what's going to be the size of this whole green View?
整个绿色视图的大小将是多少？
Well, it's gonna be the size
好吧，这将是大小
of whatever View.padding 10 returns which is the result
任何View.padding 10返回的结果
of the HStack sizing itself to fit
HStack大小调整以适应
all those aspectRatio Views plus 10 points on all sides.
所有这些aspectRatio视图在所有方面加10点。
That's gonna be the size of this whole green thing.
那将是整个绿色物体的大小。
Let's talk about Views that take
让我们来谈谈
all the space that's offered to them.
提供给他们的所有空间。
Obviously things like RoundedRectangle,
显然，诸如RoundedRectangle，
it's real easy for them.
对他们来说真的很容易。
They just crawl around a rectangle all the way
他们只是一直沿着矩形爬行
to the edges of what they're offered.
提供给他们的优势。
But what about custom Views like CardView?
但是，像CardView这样的自定义视图呢？
CardView we built out of a ZStack
我们使用ZStack构建的CardView
with RoundedRectangle, Texts,
与RoundedRectangle，文字，
we're building this thing.
我们正在建造这个东西。
It takes all the space that's offered to it,
它占用了所有提供的空间，
and there's no reason it shouldn't,
而且没有理由不应该
but it should really be adapting itself
但它确实应该适应自己
to whatever space was offered.
到提供的任何空间。
And we really see this desperately
我们真的拼命地看到了这一点
with the font size of the emoji.
带有表情符号的字体大小。
And in your homework I asked you for really small cards
在作业中，我要求您提供小卡片
to switch to a smaller font.
切换到较小的字体。
And I'm sure you'll probably realize,
而且我相信您可能会意识到，
wow, this is a really bad solution to this problem.
哇，这真是解决这个问题的糟糕方法。
And of course it is.
当然是。
Really, what we need to do and we're gonna do in our demo,
确实，在演示中我们需要做的是，我们要做的，
is pick a font size that
选择一个字体大小
is related to the size that were offered.
与所提供的尺寸有关。
Since we're gonna accept the size offered to us,
由于我们要接受提供给我们的尺寸，
we should pick this font size that fits it.
我们应该选择适合的字体大小。
So how does a View know what space was offered to it
那么，视图如何知道为其提供了什么空间
and can make that font choosing decision, for example?
并可以做出例如字体选择的决定？
Well, we do that with a special View.
好吧，我们使用特殊的视图来实现。
It's just a View,
这只是一个景观，
but it is kind of special called GeometryReader.
但这是一种特殊的名称，称为GeometryReader。
And what you do with a GeometryReader View
以及您使用GeometryReader视图做什么
is it wraps around whatever thing
它包裹着任何东西吗
that you want to adapt to the size.
您想要适应的大小。
And so this would normally just take whatever's in your body
因此，这通常会吸收您体内的任何物质
and you just wrap GeometryReader around it like this.
您只需像这样将GeometryReader包裹起来即可。
GeometryReader is just a View.
GeometryReader只是一个视图。
And I'm not showing you the obvious thing here.
我没有在这里向您展示显而易见的东西。
GeometryReader, open parentheses, content, colon,
GeometryReader，开括号，内容，冒号，
all this, just like in HStack or whatever,
所有这一切，就像在HStack中一样
this is just the content.
这仅仅是内容。
But you do notice that it has
但是你确实注意到它有
a little argument there geometry in,
里面有几何的一点争论，
similar to how ForEach has an argument
类似于ForEach具有参数的方式
which is the thing we're iterating over.
这就是我们要迭代的事情。
This also has an argument.
这也有一个论点。
So this argument is of type GeometryProxy.
因此，此参数的类型为GeometryProxy。
And this GeometryProxy is just a struct
而这个GeometryProxy只是一个结构
and it has some nice information in there,
它里面有一些不错的信息，
the most important of which is the first one you see,
最重要的是您看到的第一个
var size, that is the size you're being offered.
var size，即您所提供的大小。
The width and height CGSize is a width and height
宽度和高度CGSize是宽度和高度
that you're being offered.
被提供给你。
And you can use that size, it's in points,
您可以使用该尺寸（以磅为单位）
and of course font sizes are in points.
当然，字体大小以磅为单位。
So it's gonna be pretty easy for us to pick a font size
因此，选择字体大小将非常容易
that fits nicely in that size.
恰好适合该尺寸。
You see some other things here,
你在这里看到其他一些东西，
like the frame is actually not only the size
像框架实际上不仅大小
but it's a rectangle where we are in
但这是我们所在的矩形
a certain coordinate space like our parents coordinate space
一定的坐标空间，例如我们的父母坐标空间
or the global coordinate space,
或全局坐标空间
we can even look at if we like.
我们甚至可以看一下是否愿意。
And I'm gonna talk about the last one there,
我要谈谈那里的最后一个，
safeAreaInsets, on the next slide.
safeAreaInsets，在下一张幻灯片上。
One thing to remember about GeometeryReader,
关于GeometeryReader要记住的一件事，
it's just a View but it always accepts
它只是一个视图，但它始终接受
the space offered to it.
提供给它的空间。
And I underline that because it requires a little sinking in
我强调这是因为它需要一点点沉入
'cause you don't wanna get into a recursive loop here
因为您不想在这里进入递归循环
where the GeometryReader is reading its size
GeometryReader正在读取其大小的位置
and then you're trying to actually change the size
然后您尝试实际更改大小
of the GeometryReader based on the size that it read.
基于GeometryReader读取的大小。
It doesn't work that way.
那样行不通。
GeometryReaders always accept the size,
GeometryReader始终接受尺寸，
the space, that's offered to them,
提供给他们的空间
you have to think of it that way.
你必须这样想。
So GeometryReaders utility is just limited
因此，GeometryReaders实用程序受到限制
to knowing what size you're being offered
知道您要提供的尺寸
and adjusting how you look on the inside,
并调整您的内在外观，
that's what GeometryReader is for.
这就是GeometryReader的目的。
Don't try to twist GeometryReader into something it's not.
不要试图将GeometryReader变成不是的东西。
It's just reading your geometry,
只是在读取您的几何图形，
it's called GeometryReader,
它叫做GeometryReader，
it reads the geometry and you adapt to it
它会读取几何图形，并且您可以适应它
so you can change your font and things like that.
因此您可以更改字体等。
The safe area thing that we mentioned,
我们提到的安全区，
that safeAreaInsets that the GeometryReader tells you about.
GeometryReader告诉您的safeAreaInsets。
The safe area is best visualized
安全区域可视化程度最高
by thinking of the notch on the iPhone 10.
通过考虑iPhone 10上的缺口
Most of the time, you don't wanna be drawing up on the size
在大多数情况下，您不想草拟大小
where the notch is up there, not always though.
缺口在那里的位置，但并非总是如此。
Sometimes you might actually wanna draw up there.
有时您可能实际上想在那里画画。
And there's other safe area things too.
还有其他安全区域的事情。
Sometimes Views will add adornments
有时，视图会添加装饰
or the way they kind of draw on screen
或他们在屏幕上绘画的方式
where they don't want you drawing in certain spaces
他们不希望您在某些空间中绘画的地方
so they kind of create this safe area for you to draw in.
因此他们会创建一个安全区域供您使用。
But if you wanna go outside your safe area, you can,
但是，如果您想离开自己的安全区域，则可以，
and the way you do that is by the View modifier here,
而执行此操作的方法是通过此处的“视图”修改器，
edgesIgnoringSafeArea, and you specify which edges
edgeIgnoringSafeArea，然后指定哪些边
that you want to ignore that safe area.
您想忽略该安全区域。
So if I say edgesIgnoringSafeArea top,
因此，如果我说edgesIgnoringSafeArea回到顶部，
then that ZStack and everything in it
然后是ZStack及其中的所有内容
is going to ignore that there's a safe area on the top
会忽略顶部有一个安全区域
and just draw right up underneath that notch up there.
然后就在那刻痕的下方画上去
And so it could be photo viewing app or something,
因此，它可能是照片查看应用程序之类的东西，
maybe you wanna go all the way to the edges
也许你想一直到边缘
so you can do that here.
所以你可以在这里做。
Let's talk a little bit about how containers do what they do
让我们谈谈容器的作用
which is offer space to their Views
这为他们的意见提供了空间
and then position them.
然后放置它们。
It offers space with this modifier frame.
它为此修改器框架提供了空间。
Now, I'm not gonna talk about frame in detail here.
现在，我在这里不再详细讨论框架。
You can go look at the documentation frame
你可以去看看文件架
has quite a lot of arguments, ideal width, minimum width,
有很多参数，理想宽度，最小宽度，
all of these kinds of things to try and communicate
所有这些尝试和交流的事物
to the Views here is where the space that I'm offering you.
到这里的景观就是我为您提供的空间。
So that's all for space.
这就是空间。
And then once the View has chosen its own size,
然后，视图选择了自己的尺寸后，
then we're gonna use this modifier position to put it
那么我们将使用这个修饰符位置
somewhere in our coordinate space before the container.
容器之前我们坐标空间中的某个位置。
So that's how they do that.
因此，他们就是这样做的。
Pretty straightforward.
非常简单。
Stacks, for example, would use their alignment information
例如，堆栈将使用其对齐信息
and the spacing and all that
以及所有的间距
to figure out where their Views should go,
弄清楚他们的观点应该去哪里，
and it would set this CGPoint
它会设置这个CGPoint
which is the center of the Views,
这是视图的中心，
at the CGPoint for each of the Views.
在CGPoint中的每个视图。
By the way, it's kind of a cool little modifier here
顺便说一句，这里有点酷
called offset which will offset the View
称为偏移量，它将偏移视图
from wherever container put it.
从容器放到哪里。
So you can let the container do its job,
因此，您可以让容器完成其工作，
put the thing somewhere and then you can still offset it
把东西放在某个地方，然后你仍然可以抵消它
a little bit by something.
一点点的东西。
And the container could do this
容器可以做到这一点
but also someone else could do it.
但其他人也可以做到。
The View could do it to itself.
视图可以做到这一点。
I wanna be offset by a little bit.
我想抵消一点。
So offset is kind of a fun little one.
因此，抵消是一个有趣的小家伙。
We don't use offset that much
我们不用太多的偏移量
but I just wanna let you know it's there.
但我只想让你知道它的存在。
Now, for Memorize, we're gonna use frame
现在，为了记住，我们将使用框架
and position to create our own Container View
和位置来创建我们自己的容器视图
which is kind of like a stack.
有点像堆栈。
It's gonna be called a Grid and it's 2D, rows and columns,
它被称为网格，它是2D，行和列，
instead of just a horizontal row
而不只是水平行
which is a pretty sad-looking game,
这是一个看起来很伤心的游戏，
if I do say so myself right now.
如果我现在就这样说的话。
And we obviously want that to be rows and columns.
我们显然希望它是行和列。
We'll do that by using frame and position
我们将通过使用框架和位置来做到这一点
to create our own container.
创建我们自己的容器。
So we're gonna go back to the demo today.
所以我们今天要回到演示。
I'd love to have time to actually go do that container,
我很想有时间去做那个容器，
but we don't have that, end of lecture three here.
但是我们没有，第三节课结束。
I do have a short demo though I'm going to do
我会做一个简短的演示
just to show you how GeometryReader works.
只是向您展示GeometryReader的工作原理。
And what we're gonna do is what I've been talking about,
而我们要做的就是我一直在谈论的东西，
make our font, our emoji font,
制作我们的字体，表情符号字体，
size better to the space we're offered
尺寸更适合我们提供的空间
using a GeometryReader.
使用GeometryReader。
While I'm there, I may do a quick little thing
当我在那里的时候，我可能会做一件小事
where I'm gonna show you the best way
我要告诉你最好的方法
or the kind of way we've all agreed on
或我们大家都同意的那种方式
to collect magic numbers in our code.
在我们的代码中收集魔术数字。
If you already have one in there like cornerRadius 10,
如果您已经有一个如cornerRadius 10这样的设备，
that 10 is a magic number,
那10是个魔术数字，
it really shouldn't be embedded in our code.
它确实不应该嵌入我们的代码中。
There's kind of a canonical way in Swift to take that out
Swift中有一种规范的方法可以将其删除
and put it in its own little space
并放在自己的小空间
so it's well-documented and typed.
因此，它有充分的文档记录和类型。
Now we'll start our next lecture though,
现在，我们开始下一个演讲，
using GeometryReader and also generics
使用GeometryReader和泛型
with protocols and functions as types
具有协议和功能类型
to make this beautiful little simple Grid View
使这个美丽的小简单的网格视图
that's just gonna be like an HStack.
那就像是一个HStack。
We're gonna replace our HStack by just using this Grid View
我们将仅使用此Grid View来替换HStack
and make our cards be in a nice grid.
并使我们的卡片排列在一个漂亮的网格中。
So let's hop into that demo
因此，让我们跳入该演示
and then that'll be the end of this lecture.
然后这将是本讲座的结尾。
Now in your homework,
现在在您的作业中，
you were asked to adjust the font choice here
您被要求在此处调整字体选择
to fit really small cards because small cards,
适合小卡片，因为小卡片，
the font we chose, large title was too big.
我们选择的字体，大标题太大。
And that might have fixed it just for small cards
这可能已经解决了，仅适用于小卡片
but I made you do that almost to realize,
但是我让你这样做几乎是为了意识到，
well, that's no good solution, especially when we're
好吧，这不是一个好的解决方案，尤其是当我们
in landscape where even large title is way too small.
在连大标题都太小的风景中。
So what we really want is for our card
所以我们真正想要的是我们的卡
to pick a font that uses all the space.
选择使用所有空间的字体。
That's really what we wanna do.
那确实是我们想要做的。
So how are we going to do that?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
Well, we're gonna do that with a special View.
好吧，我们将使用特殊的View来做到这一点。
It's another View, just like HStack is a View
这是另一个视图，就像HStack是一个视图
and ForEach is a View and ZStack is a View, Text is a View.
ForEach是一个视图，ZStack是一个视图，Text是一个视图。
These are all just Views.
这些都是视图。
There's a special View
有一个特殊的看法
that is called the GeometryReader View.
这就是所谓的GeometryReader视图。
So GeometryReader has one argument
所以GeometryReader有一个参数
which is the content that it's going to display
这将是要显示的内容
inside of itself which is just another View like our card,
本身就是另一个像我们的卡片一样的视图，
the ZStack that will make our card,
ZStack可以制作我们的卡，
but it has a nice argument here called geometry,
但是这里有一个很好的论点，叫做几何
just like ForEach was a View that had an argument here
就像ForEach是在这里有论点的View
but it also had this content argument
但它也有这种内容论点
and it provided the Card that it was iterating through.
它提供了要遍历的Card。
Same thing here, GeometryReader, it has content,
同样，GeometryReader，它具有内容，
asks for a View, but it provides this special geometry.
要求一个视图，但它提供了这种特殊的几何形状。
And we're gonna look at this little variable
我们将看看这个小变量
that is given to you inside here
在这里给你的
'cause we can look at this
因为我们可以看一下
and see what the size of our View is.
并查看我们的视图的大小。
Now notice that when we put our code,
现在注意，当我们放置代码时，
our ZStack, inside of a GeometryReader content,
我们的ZStack，位于GeometryReader内容中，
we got these requires self.thing.
我们得到了这些需要self.thing。
So to go through here and do a fix out of this one,
因此，请通过此处并对此进行修复，
fix that one as well, pick that up.
修理那个，捡起来。
So what is this?
那是什么
Let's take a look at the documentation for GeometryReader.
让我们看一下GeometryReader的文档。
So I'm gonna do Option + Click to look at GeometryReader.
因此，我将执行Option +单击以查看GeometryReader。
And you can see here struct GeometryReader.
您可以在此处看到struct GeometryReader。
It's got a don't care called Content
不用管它叫Content
where that Content is a View.
该内容是一个视图。
And so now, hopefully, you are starting to understand
所以现在，希望您开始了解
what that means, where Content is a View, right?
这意味着“内容是视图”，对吗？
Content is a don't care, View is a protocol.
内容不在乎，视图是协议。
So we've turned that don't care into a,
所以我们已经把无关紧要变成了
well we care a little bit, right?
好吧，我们有点在意吧？
We care that the Content of a GeometryReader is a View,
我们关心的是GeometryReader的内容是一个View，
but otherwise it can be anything it wants.
但是否则它可以是它想要的任何东西。
And so I'm gonna open that in the documentation
所以我要在文档中打开它
and take a look, see what it says.
看看它怎么说。
And here's the init.
这是初始化。
You can see that it takes this one argument content
您可以看到它需要这一参数内容
which actually you should be recognizing this syntax here
您实际上应该在这里识别此语法
because really, it takes a function
因为真的，它需要一个功能
that returns this Content don't care,
返回此内容的内容不在乎，
which we know is actually a we care a little bit Content
我们知道实际上是我们关心的一点内容
where Content colon View
内容冒号视图
so we know it has to be a View.
因此我们知道它必须是View。
And so that's a function, function that takes an argument,
这就是一个带有参数的函数
GeometryProxy, and returns this don't care Content.
GeometryProxy，并返回此无关内容。
Don't worry about that @ escaping there.
不用担心@逃到那里。
We'll be talking about that in the weeks to come.
我们将在接下来的几周内谈论这一点。
So let's click on this GeometryProxy and see its decoration.
因此，让我们单击此GeometryProxy并查看其装饰。
Here it is, and you can see it has the things
在这里，您可以看到其中包含的东西
we talked about in the slides.
我们在幻灯片中谈到了。
Now I'm gonna focus obviously on the size right here.
现在，我将重点显然放在此处的尺寸上。
So let's click on that.
因此，让我们单击它。
And you can see that size is just a CGSize,
您会看到大小只是CGSize，
it's get only, it's read only.
它只有get，它是只读的。
It's just going to tell us the width and height
只是要告诉我们宽度和高度
that we've been offered to draw this View in.
我们已经提供了绘制此视图的方法。
So that's exactly what we want.
这正是我们想要的。
We want this geometry size right here.
我们希望此几何尺寸就在这里。
And what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna have my CardView
我要做的是拥有CardView
take ownership for setting its own font right here.
在这里设置自己的字体以取得所有权。
So it's gonna go to font.
因此，它将使用字体。
So I'm no longer setting the font in the game itself.
因此，我不再在游戏本身中设置字体。
I'm letting the Card set its own font
我让卡设置自己的字体
which is probably better encapsulation anyway.
无论如何，这可能是更好的封装。
Why we're here, of course,
为什么我们在这里，
we don't need this colon content thing just like HStack
我们不需要像HStack这样的冒号内容
and all these other things.
以及所有其他这些东西。
We can get rid of that and get rid of that
我们可以摆脱它，摆脱它
so this looks a lot cleaner there.
所以这看起来很干净。
So we wanna do a font here, so write some font,
所以我们想在这里做一个字体，所以写一些字体，
whose size is based on that geometry size.
其尺寸基于该几何尺寸。
So I'm gonna create a system font,
所以我要创建系统字体，
just different ways to make the system font right here,
只是在这里制作系统字体的不同方法，
styles and sizes.
样式和大小。
So I'm just gonna pick size.
所以我只是选择尺寸。
I want a CGFloat with the size, the point size.
我想要一个CGFloat，其大小为磅值。
And remember the point size of font
并记住字体的磅值
is related to the point width and the point height there.
与那里的点宽和点高有关。
So I'm actually gonna pick the minimum of the width
所以我实际上要选择最小的宽度
to the height 'cause I don't necessarily want
因为我不一定要
to depend on knowing what my aspect ratio here is.
取决于知道我的宽高比是多少。
And so I'm just gonna pick the minimum of those two
所以我只选择这两个中的最小值
to make sure that I pick a font that fits.
确保我选择合适的字体。
So that's min geometry size width
所以这是最小几何尺寸宽度
and the geometry size height.
以及几何尺寸高度。
So I'm using that size var that we saw
所以我使用的是我们看到的那个大小变量
that's in this GeometryProxy right here.
就在这里的GeometryProxy中。
And maybe we could just try this.
也许我们可以尝试一下。
Let's just pick a font size that is the minimum of these two
我们只选择这两种字体中最小的一种
and just see what this looks like.
然后看看它是什么样子。
So let's run this.
因此，让我们运行它。
Look at that.
看那个。
So that is a much closer size and you even got smaller.
这样的尺寸更接近，甚至更小。
But this is actually a little too big.
但这实际上太大了。
It's got a little too big there.
那里太大了。
Maybe that's just because plot point sizes
也许只是因为绘图点大小
aren't exactly the width of the font.
不完全是字体的宽度。
It may probably closer related to the height,
它可能与高度有关，
but also we do put a little stroke around the edge
但是我们也确实在边缘上做了一些笔触
that takes away a little space as well.
也会占用一点空间。
So probably I need some sort of constant multiplier here,
所以可能我需要某种常数乘数
like maybe times 75%, 0.75, something like that.
例如大约75％，0.75。
And 75% actually looks pretty good.
而75％的人看起来确实不错。
Looks good when it's big, looks good when it's small.
大的时候看起来不错，小的时候看起来不错。
Before we finish up lecture three,
在完成第三讲之前，
I wanna take just a moment here
我想在这里花点时间
to talk about a coding style issue.
谈论编码风格问题。
I don't often talk too much about coding style,
我不太常谈论编码风格，
purely for time constraints in these lectures
纯粹出于时间限制
but this time I am going to mention this.
但是这次我要提一下。
'cause it's a little bit of a segue
因为这有点塞古
into how we're going to structure our View code
我们将如何构建我们的View代码
to make it as readable as possible.
使它更具可读性。
This problem I'm worried about is these magic numbers.
我担心的问题是这些幻数。
We've created these blue magic numbers
我们已经创建了这些蓝色魔术数字
and started to sprinkle them out throughout our code.
并开始在整个代码中散布它们。
That's not very good coding style.
那不是很好的编码风格。
SwiftUI is declarative.
SwiftUI是声明性的。
We're essentially declaring the UI directly here.
我们实质上是在这里直接声明UI。
We're not calling functions to tell it to build itself,
我们不是在调用函数来告诉它自己构建，
we are declaring it right here.
我们在这里宣布。
And when we do that,
当我们这样做时
these blue numbers end up being kind of the knobs
这些蓝色的数字最终变成了旋钮
that we can turn to fine tune the way our View looks
我们可以调整视图的外观
and get it just right.
并使其正确。
Well, right now our knobs are just spread
好吧，现在我们的旋钮刚刚散开
all over the place here.
在这里的所有地方。
Really nice if we could have a control panel.
如果我们能有一个控制面板，那真是太好了。
So I'm going to create a little control panel.
因此，我将创建一个小的控制面板。
I'm gonna comment here to MARK it drawing constants,
我要在这里评论以标记它的绘制常数，
I'm gonna call it,
我要称呼它
and put all my drawing constants down here
并把我所有的绘图常数放在这里
as just vars and lets and functions on my struct.
就像vars一样，让和在我的结构上起作用。
And this idea of putting vars and lets and functions
以及放置vars，let和函数的想法
in your struct to clean up
在你的结构中清理
or fix magic numbers in your View, really important.
或在您的视图中固定魔术数字，这非常重要。
You're gonna see that most Views have
您将看到大多数视图具有
a few vars and lets and funcs down here
一些变量，让我们在这里进行功能
to make this look as clean and understandable as possible.
使外观看起来尽可能整洁易懂。
So let's use this idea to get these magic numbers out here.
因此，让我们使用这个想法来获得这些神奇的数字。
These happened to be constants.
这些碰巧是常数。
So I'm gonna use let.
所以我要用let。
Remember, let is like var except
记住，让我们就像var一样
for let means it's a constant.
因为let表示它是一个常数。
So let's do the corner radius up there, cornerRadius.
因此，让我们在此处进行转角半径cornerRadius的设置。
You might think you could say cornerRadius equals 10
您可能会认为您可以说cornerRadius等于10
but this doesn't work and I'm gonna show you why here.
但这是行不通的，我将向您展示为什么。
If you hold down the option key, remember, and click,
如果按住Option键，请记住并单击，
it'll tell you the declaration
它会告诉你宣言
of this thing that you clicked on.
您点击的东西
In our case, it's our cornerRadius
就我们而言，这是我们的角落
and it has been typed as an Int.
并且已将其键入为Int。
Remember that if we say let a var equal something
请记住，如果我们说让var等于某物
and we don't specify it's type,
我们没有指定它的类型，
Swift will infer it.
Swift会推断出来。
And here it's looking at this 10 and referring,
这里是看这十个参考
looks like an Int.
看起来像一个Int。
That's not what we want.
那不是我们想要的。
All of these blue numbers in here are CGFloats,
这些蓝色的数字都是CGFloats，
floating point numbers we use to draw.
我们用来绘制的浮点数。
Now, I can't even just say 10.0.
现在，我什至不能只说10.0。
If I do that and Option + Click,
如果我这样做，并且按住Option +单击，
it thinks it's a Double.
它认为这是一个Double。
These are not double precision floating point numbers.
这些不是双精度浮点数。
This Double struct is not the same as a CGFloat struct.
此Double结构与CGFloat结构不同。
So I have to explicitly type this, CGFloat.
因此，我必须明确键入CGFloat。
And that's not necessarily that burdensome or onerous,
那并不一定是那么繁重或繁重，
it's kind of nice in a way to remind myself
提醒自己的方式很好
these are drawing constants down here.
这些在这里画出常数。
Let's do our other ones.
让我们做其他的吧。
We got the edgeLineWidth.
我们得到了edgeLineWidth。
There's another constant we have up there,
我们还有另一个常数
that number three,
第三
and of course we have this 0.75
当然我们有0.75
which is really like a scaling factor for our fonts.
这真的像我们字体的缩放比例。
I'm gonna call it fontScaleFactor,
我将其命名为fontScaleFactor，
that's also a CGFloat, 0.75.
这也是CGFloat，0.75。
Now that I have these down here,
现在我将这些放在这里，
I can replace all my magic numbers with these
我可以用这些替换所有的魔术数字
and this becomes the knobs on my control panel.
这将成为我控制面板上的旋钮。
So let's do that.
因此，让我们这样做。
We've got this one.
我们有这个。
I'm gonna copy and paste, make this go a little quicker.
我要复制并粘贴，使此过程更快一点。
And over here, this three is this edge line right here
在这里，这三个是这里的边缘线
and our fontScaleFactor here is this 0.75 here.
而我们的fontScaleFactor在这里是0.75。
This is nice.
很好
This actually makes this code read nicely as well,
实际上，这也使这段代码读起来也很不错，
pretty much like the English language,
非常像英语
trying to understand what's going on.
试图了解正在发生的事情。
However, you notice it's introduced
但是，您会注意到它的引入
a whole slew of errors here.
这里有很多错误。
They're actually all the same error.
它们实际上都是相同的错误。
It's the dreaded explicit self.
这是可怕的显性自我。
to make capture semantics explicit.
使捕获语义明确。
And we could just, maybe fix this one and click here
我们可以解决这个问题，然后单击此处
and then fix this one and I click it and fix it,
然后修复它，然后单击并修复它，
but I'm gonna show you a trick for avoiding this self. thing
但我将向您展示避免这种自我的技巧。事情
in this common case of GeometryReader.
在这种常见的GeometryReader情况下。
So whenever you do a GeometryReader,
因此，每当您执行GeometryReader时，
the stuff inside is always gonna complain
里面的东西总会抱怨
about this self dot.
关于这个自我点。
By the way, same thing with ForEach.
顺便说一句，ForEach也是如此。
ForEach stuff inside is gonna complain about self dot.
里面的每样东西都会抱怨自我点。
Not every View does that but those two do
并非每个View都这样做，但是那两个
and they're commonly used.
并且它们是常用的。
I'm gonna create a func which I'm gonna call body for size,
我要创建一个功能，我称其为本体，
CGSize, and it's gonna return my body,
CGSize，它将使我的身体恢复原状，
so that's gonna be some View just like I can have
就像我可以拥有的那样，这将是一些视图
some View be the type of this var,
一些View是此var的类型，
I can have some View be the return type of this func.
我可以让一些View作为此函子的返回类型。
And I'm gonna put my body,
我要把我的身体，
to cut it out of here, and put it in here,
从这里剪下来，放在这里，
and then just call this function in my GeometryReader,
然后在我的GeometryReader中调用此函数，
self.body for the geometry size.
用于几何尺寸的self.body。
This code cleaned up actually kind of nicely.
这段代码实际上清理得很好。
This makes perfect sense.
这是很合理的。
And this code now is no longer embedded
现在该代码不再嵌入
inside this GeometryReader like this
在这样的GeometryReader中
so you don't need these self dots.
因此您不需要这些自我点。
So I can get rid of that one
所以我可以摆脱那一个
and that one and that one and this one.
那一那一那。
All those self dots are gone.
所有那些自我点都消失了。
What's more here, I didn't pass the entire geometry
更重要的是，我没有通过整个几何
to this body, just the size, the geometry size var.
到这个物体，只是尺寸，几何尺寸var。
So down here, I don't need to say geometry.size.
所以在这里，我不需要说geometry.size。
This geometry.size is now just size,
现在这个geometry.size就是size，
this size that I passed in.
我传入的这个大小。
So that made this code look a lot nicer
这样使这段代码看起来更好
and I almost always recommend,
我几乎总是建议，
at least for the next couple of months
至少接下来的几个月
until they put that Swift self.change in there
直到他们把Swift的self.change放在那里
so the self. is not causing this problem anymore.
自我。不再导致此问题。
This is a real clean way to have this code
这是拥有此代码的真正干净的方法
not have to worry about self dot.
不必担心自我点。
And you can do the same thing body for item in a ForEach
您可以在ForEach中为项目做相同的事情
'cause ForEach is gonna cause that self. problem as well.
因为每个人都会导致那个自我。问题。
We could do one other thing here.
我们可以在这里做另一件事。
Here, I could have a func
在这里，我可以有一个功能
for the font size called fontSize for size,
对于称为fontSize的字体大小，
have it return a font size which is also a CGFloat,
它返回的字体大小也是CGFloat，
and put this code right here down in here
并将这段代码放在这里
so that this just reads fontSize for size.
这样就可以读取fontSize的大小。
You might think this is a very simple expression,
您可能会认为这是一个非常简单的表达，
I don't really need to turn it into its own func here,
我真的不需要在这里将其变成自己的功能，
but again, you can't make this too simple.
但是同样，您不能使它变得太简单。
You really want to have this be simple as possible.
您真的想让它尽可能简单。
And sometimes you're forced to make it simple.
有时您不得不使其变得简单。
These ifs, as I explained,
正如我所解释的，
can't be arbitrarily complex expressions.
不能是任意复杂的表达式。
So sometimes this needs to be a function
所以有时候这需要一个函数
that returns a Bool,
返回一个布尔，
not in this case, 'cause this is simple Bool.
不是在这种情况下，因为这是简单的布尔。
But making these little one liner functions
但是让这些小班轮发挥作用
that make this body look cleaner, very common.
使这个身体看起来更干净，很常见。
Here, we might even not have to have this fontScaleFactor
在这里，我们甚至不必拥有这个fontScaleFactor
be its own separate let
成为自己的独立
because you can kind of think of the font size
因为您可以考虑字体大小
as just part of the drawing constants.
作为绘图常量的一部分。
This is the constant font size for a given size.
这是给定大小的恒定字体大小。
So that's it for lecture three.
这就是第三讲。
And we're gonna dive right back in,
我们要马上潜回去
start with lecture four and continue with this demo
从第四讲开始，并继续进行此演示
and make our HStack up here be a 2D grid.
并使我们的HStack成为2D网格。
We're gonna learn a lot of stuff doing that.
我们将学到很多东西。
- [Announcer] For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
-[播音员]有关更多信息，请访问stanford.edu。